<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	<!-- generator="WordPress/5.3.4" created="2020-08-12 02:42" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Insights Blog</title>
	<link>http://blog.eventbank.com</link>
	<description>All about event management, membership automation and the latest news from EventBank.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://blog.eventbank.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://blog.eventbank.com</wp:base_blog_url>

		<wp:author><wp:author_id>51</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[carl]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[carl.wegner@eventbank.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Carl Wegner]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Carl]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Wegner]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>52</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[camila]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[camila.cardwell@eventbank.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Camila Cardwell]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Camila]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Cardwell]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>25</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[robert]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[robert.rafferty@eventbank.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Robert Rafferty]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Robert]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Rafferty]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>50</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[jeremy]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[jeremy.smith@eventbank.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Jeremy Smith]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Jeremy]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Smith]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

				
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.4</generator>

<image>
	<url>http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/cropped-EventBank-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Insights Blog</title>
	<link>http://blog.eventbank.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 

		<item>
		<title>27 Strategies to Run a Successful Webinar</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/successful-webinar-strategies/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 09:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carl]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=17394</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Running a webinar can be a daunting task and may not be a process you know very much about. However, companies around the world have been implementing webinars as part of their strategies in order to adapt to the changing business and social environments caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. Anyone can launch a webinar but to make a webinar successful is no easy task. However, here we have provided 27 Strategies that can help you run a successful webinar.
<h3 id="top">Quick Reads</h3>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 216px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 216px;">
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 216px;"><a href="#price">Price Considerations</a>
<a href="#chatroom">Chat Room Experience</a>
<a href="#agenda">On-Screen Agenda</a>
<a href="#links">Individual Zoom Links</a>
<a href="#platform">Solid Platform</a>
<a href="#networking">Networking Integration</a>
<a href="#contingency">Contingency Plan</a>
<a href="#reminders">Reminders</a>
<a href="#promotions">Promotions</a></td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 216px;"><a href="#earlybird">Early Bird Discounts</a>
<a href="#consistency">Consistency</a>
<a href="#feedback">Feedback</a>
<a href="#accessibility">Accessibility</a>
<a href="#presenters">Trained Presenters</a>
<a href="#itcrew">On-site IT Crew</a>
<a href="#deck">Amazing slide deck</a>
<a href="#punctual">Be Punctual</a>
<a href="#mistakes">Acknowledge Mistakes</a></td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 216px;"><a href="#marketing">Strong Promotion</a>
<a href="#audience">Know Your Audience</a>
<a href="#branding">Visual Branding</a>
<a href="#mobile">Mobile Device Integration</a>
<a href="#scheduel">Stay on Schedule</a>
<a href="#faqs">Present FAQ’s</a>
<a href="#timing">Timing</a>
<a href="#recording">Webinar Recording</a>
<a href="#launch">Start Your Webinar</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="price">1. Price Considerations</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17382 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/money-webinars@2x.png" alt="paid webinars" width="1920" height="1030" />

Pricing your webinar is a very important aspect of running a paid webinar. A webinar that is too expensive can dissuade potential audience members from participating, however, a webinar that is priced too cheap can lower the perceived value of it. Ensure that your pricing point increases the perceived value of your webinar, while not so high as to dissuade people from joining.
<h2 id="chatroom">2. Chat Room Experience</h2>
A chat room experience is a helpful tool that can increase the perceived value of your webinar. The ability to interact with other audience members of the webinar can be a helpful tool that keeps people engaged and less likely to leave the webinar early. Ensure that you as a speaker should ask questions to the audience and explicitly ask them to enter their thoughts in the chatbox. This can ensure increased engagement and keep people from leaving your webinar early.
<h2 id="agenda">3. On-Screen Agenda</h2>
People like to have a road map to see where they are going. Being kept in the blind can trigger thoughts of confusion and trepidation on what would come next. Having an agenda can help audience members follow along easier and capture the most important topics that they wanted to focus on during the webinar. In addition, an agenda does not only help your audience members but can also improve the speaker’s time management and experience. This can ensure the speaker stays on topic and manages his or her time in a manner that does not extend the duration of the webinar to encroach on audience member’s personal time.
<h2 id="links">4. Individual Zoom Links</h2>
Zoom is a very commonly used Web Conference software. Around 300 Million daily participants join Zoom meetings each day. Since it is so commonly used, most people will not need to install another piece of software to join your webinars when Zoom is used. The one main issue with Zoom meetings is that they can be joined by just having access to a link.

This means that if one person pays for your webinar they will be able to share that link to an unlimited number of people to join the webinar as well. Due to this fact, you need to have an integrated Zoom software that generates individual links that only a single person can use. Once you do that, you will be able to charge for webinars hosted through Zoom.
<h2 id="platform">5. Solid Platform</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16882 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-COVID@2x.png" alt="webinar tips" width="1920" height="1030" />

When hosting a webinar, many technological factors are at play. This creates a need that none of them go wrong during your webinar. Sometimes technological issues that happen can be out of your control, but regardless it conveys a sense of unprofessionalism. Ensure the platform that you are utilizing is a solid platform that has been tested and as many bugs as possible are eliminated prior to hosting your webinar.
<h2 id="networking">6. Networking Integration</h2>
Audience members who join a webinar tend to be working in the same industry or interested in similar topics. To create additional value for your audience members, who join your webinar, you should integrate an ability for them to able to network with each other. If audience members were able to design and send virtual business cards to each other, they would be gaining a lot more value from your webinar.

This can attract a new segment of audience members who join your webinar with people who have the same interests or work in the same industry as people who commonly join your webinar.
<h2 id="contingency">7. Contingency Plan</h2>
If something goes wrong when hosting your webinar, you should always have a back plan in place. If a speaker is not able to connect to the webinar for some reason, or drops out due to connection issues, another speaker should be already in place and ready to take over at a moment's notice. This ensures that your webinar runs its full length without extending the length of the webinar.
<h2 id="reminders">8. Reminders</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16810 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-phone@2x.png" alt="mobile notifications" width="2400" height="1288" />

Reminders are important to send out to your audience members that have paid to attend your webinar. You do not want audience members missing your webinar because they have forgotten. However, reminders do not solely need to be based upon audience members who have registered, they can be sent to everyone in your network to increase the knowledge about your webinar. This could increase the number of registrations for your events.
<h2 id="promotions">9. Promotions</h2>
Promotions are a beneficial way to convince more people to register for your webinars. Promotions give a larger incentive for potential members to purchase a ticket to your webinar. 64% of consumers tend to wait for things to go on sale before purchasing them, so when a promotion is present, potential audience members will be more inclined to purchase tickets to your webinar.

Potential promotions can be a “season” of webinars at a lower price than if the webinars are purchased separately. Another promotional idea could be to include a promotional code at the end of your webinars. These codes can be given out to audience members who stay until the end of your webinars for a lower price on the tickets of the next webinar you are hosting.
<h2 id="earlybird">10. Early Bird Discounts</h2>
Early Bird Discounts can add up to 80% of your sales and they are a great way to boost the number of tickets you sell to potential audience members. When people see a discount next to the full price, they are more inclined to purchase the product or service because they believe that they believed they have rewarded something when they see the urgency of such a discount. While you may not be making as much revenue from each ticket as you would from selling full-price tickets, creating a sense of urgency can increase the number of audience members attending your webinar.
<h2 id="consistency">11. Consistency</h2>
People crave consistency in the very inconsistent world that we live in. Consistency often develops into a feeling of trust. Consistency can be achieved in two different aspects, the consistency of the webinar format and slides, and the consistency of the recurrence of webinars. If you ensure these two aspects stay consistent, audience members will start to trust you and begin to attend more of your webinars.
<h2 id="feedback">12. Feedback</h2>
Feedback is always important after a webinar because there is always room for improvement. As the presenter or host of the webinar, you may not see the potential small changes that could make that can vastly improve the experience of the audience members. By sending out a feedback form with open-ended questions, the feedback you receive can improve your webinars for your current audience members, as well as, improve the experience for future audience members.
<h2 id="accessibility">13. Accessibility</h2>
Accessibility is important to consider for your webinar. Programs need to be easy for your audience members to learn to use. Programs that need to be downloaded and installed should not have a steep learning curve, to not deter potential audience members from joining your webinars. Ideally, you would use a commonly used software that audience members would have previously downloaded, to mitigate a barrier of entry to your webinars.
<h2 id="presenters">14. Trained Presenters</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17365 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sem-webinars@2x-1.png" alt="webinar speaker" width="1920" height="1030" />

You need to ensure that the people presenting the webinars are familiar with the software and are apt at dealing with frequently encountered issues swiftly while still presenting. This ensures a smooth transition between technical issues and the webinar.
<h2 id="itcrew">15. On-site IT Crew</h2>
On-site IT crews can help people with issues they encounter during the webinar. The ability to do a quick fix will create a positive webinar experience. To have an IT crew during the webinar, audience members can directly ask them questions during the webinar when they are having some issues rather than asking the presenter, disrupting the webinar. This creates more value for the audience member if they are having an issue because they would be able to attend the webinar as soon as the IT crew fixes their issue, rather than having to wait for the recorded webinar to be published
<h2 id="deck">16. Amazing slide deck</h2>
An amazing slide deck is an important factor in your webinars since the audience members will be mainly watching your slide decks as you present. Ensure that there is a professional standard set that you want to convey to your audience members. In addition to this, you should also verify that your slide deck is interesting. An uninteresting slide deck will bore your audience members and can drive them away from being repeat audience members of your webinar.
<h2 id="punctual">17. Be Punctual</h2>
Always arrive to the meeting early, because some people may join the meeting a bit early and you don’t want them thinking there are technical issues when they try to join. Being early doesn’t mean you start any earlier than planned, just be one step ahead so you can start your webinar on time. Planning to be early also ensures that if there are any technical issues from your end, you have time to fix it before the planned start time of the webinar.
<h2 id="mistakes">18. Acknowledge Mistakes and Technical Issues</h2>
When presenting your webinar, ensure that any mistakes that you see are noted and expressed to the audience. It is better to acknowledge your mistake before your audience points it out. If an audience member points out a mistake before you do, it can convey a sense of unprofessionalism. To point out and acknowledge your mistakes early on, it shows the audience that you do understand what you are talking about, however, you are still human and prone to mistakes.

In addition, if you should run into technical problems during the presentation of the webinar, acknowledge that you recognize the issue and have the tech team on standby work to resolve the issue as soon as possible.
<h2 id="promotion">19. Strong Promotion</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16470 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-2@2x-2.png" alt="marketing trends in 2020" width="1920" height="1030" />

Promotion is an integral part of potential audience members learning about your webinar. For you to market it well, ensure you do market research on what platforms that your target audience members frequent. If you can market on those platforms, you would be reasonable to expect to have a larger number of the audience compared to promoting on a platform that your target audience members do not frequent.
<h2 id="audience">20. Know Your Audience</h2>
Ensure that you understand your target audience when picking a speaker, setting the webinar time, and also creating the slide deck. If you understand that your audience is individuals in the US wants to learn about Event Management Software, you would not be posting visuals on medical trends or hosting the webinar at 3pm in China which would be 3am on the East Coast of the United States. Ensure you have established your target audience, and cater to what they would like to see.
<h2 id="branding">21. Visual Branding</h2>
Your visual brand is the first touchpoint with your customers. Ensure that you have strong visual branding because if you do, potential audience members may develop a preliminary sense of trust in you. The visual brand needs to be consistent in all marketing materials or any materials that potential audience members will see.

A weak, inconsistent visual brand will portray a sense of unprofessionalism and can deter potential audience members from joining. But a strong visual brand will have them interested, which is the first step that eventually converts them into audience members for your webinar.
<h2 id="mobile">22. Mobile Device Integration</h2>
25% of people sign into webinars from a mobile device, and to include this population of audience members into your webinar audience, implement mobile device compatibility into your webinar. This does not create a sense of exclusivity and deter the members of your audience who plan to sign in on a mobile device.
<h2 id="schedule">23. Stay on Schedule</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17196 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/tips-communities-going-digital.png" alt="webinar technology" width="1200" height="644" />

Always assume your audience members may have commitments before or after your webinars. Ensure that you start your webinars on time and also end within the allotted time slot you have promoted. This ensures that audience members no longer need to leave your webinars early.

Moreover, it shows that you value your audience members' time. This will create a positive experience for your audience members and will increase your retention of your audience members because they know that they can plan things after your webinar and ensures the efficiency of planning their schedules.
<h2 id="faqs">24. Present FAQ’s</h2>
Having audience members participate in a Q &amp; A may be a daunting task for them. In order for some questions to be asked, you might want to start by establishing some frequently asked questions and answer them. Not only does this answer some of your audience members' questions, but it can also encourage audience members to ask other questions that they may have.
<h2 id="timing">25. Timing</h2>
The timing of your webinars can affect the number of potential audience members joining your webinars. You would need to pick a time that is convenient for your audience members to join. If the timing for them is not ideal they would not buy tickets to your webinar. Statistically speaking, most people join webinars between the 11am to 2pm time slots in the middle of the workweek. You can use this as a basis for your hosting times
<h2 id="recording">26. Webinar Recording</h2>
Extenuating circumstances always come up in our lives and can alter our original plans. This could mean that some of your audience members may not be able to join a certain webinar on a certain date after they registered for it. You should not penalize your audience members for it, rather, you should have a recorded version of your webinar uploaded to those who signed up for the webinar. Not only can people who missed the webinar watch it, people who are going back to reuse it for reference can also re-watch it.
<h2 id="launch">27. Start Your Webinar</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17341 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/emails-blog@2x.png" alt="webinar invite email examples" width="2400" height="1288" />

Our last tip is for you to start planning your next webinar. To have a successful webinar, you must first start planning for one and hosting it. Not all of these strategies apply to everyone and you should pick which ones can be implemented for your own webinars. Remember these tips and if you learn anything new we hope you share it with us as well! We hope your next webinar runs smoothly and turns out amazing.

If you're looking for a way to enhance your webinars, monetize ticket sales for webinars, or otherwise deliver a one-of-a-kind webinar experience, <a href="https://get.eventbank.com/webinar-solution/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=webinarsuccess"><strong>Book a Demo</strong></a> with EventBank and we'll show you how our platform can do help you with a feature-rich set of tools and options for your webinars.

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top.</strong></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17394</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-01 09:41:33]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-01 09:41:33]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[successful-webinar-strategies]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="digital"><![CDATA[digital]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="event-management"><![CDATA[Event Management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="strategy"><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="webinar"><![CDATA[webinar]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[27 Strategies to Run a Successful Webinar]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[See how these 27 strategies for running a successful webinar can help your business reach a wider audience, engage them better, and go viral.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17548]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Providing Value to Members in a Post-Pandemic World</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/member-value-post-pandemic/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 02:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[camila]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=17578</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Asia Pacific’s top association leaders came together in a recent webinar to discuss how associations can provide value to their members on the road to recovery from coronavirus. The actions that associations take over the next few months will make the difference in associations that find success and those who don’t.

The panel included the following panelists: Datuk Dr. Raj Abdul Karim, the President of the Malaysian Council of Child Welfare and Chair of the Malaysian Society of Association Executives; Charles Villasenor, the Chairman at the Philippine Council of Associations and Association Executives; Antonio Codinach, the Regional Business Director of APAC of PCMA; and Marcel Ewals, the Director of Associations and Marketing of MCI Group. The panelists gave insights into the impact of the pandemic and strategies to help associations when moving forward.
<h2>Important Factors</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16672 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/value-copy-58@1x.png" alt="conference networking tips" width="1200" height="644" />

The pandemic has undoubtedly left the event industry in huge trouble. It’s a wake-up call for businesses: it’s the most serious shift the industry has faced and is forcing associations to rethink their business models. We may never go back to the same industry that we had before. Taking this into account, there are a couple main things that associations must do in order to move forward.

First, remember that you hold influence in your society! The trajectory of the event business is going to be largely impacted by the decisions of your local government. It’s extremely important to advocate the government to support local businesses during the shutdown and as reopening begins. This could mean the difference between surviving the pandemic and shutting down.

Another thing to consider is the importance of communication with your members. Use online events to reach your audience. Ask what they need in the current situation and how your association can help them. Get feedback on how you’re doing and ask what challenges they expect to experience in the future.

Use this communication to provide content and education that offers value to them. The more you understand the needs of your members, the more you will be able to curate differentiated content.

Finally, associations must consider the effect that an online work environment is having on their employees. Without face to face interaction, it is harder to communicate with employees and maintain morale. Association leaders must communicate with their employees and help to keep them motivated within the associations.

Develop communication plans, immediately shift all efforts online, and reach out to employees individually. If your employees are not motivated and contributing towards moving forward, it could mean failure for your association.
<h2>Immediate Short-Term Strategy</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16661 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/value-copy-20@2x.png" alt="chamber of commerce myths and misconceptions" width="1920" height="1030" />

This crisis is similar to those of the past, such as 9/11 or the market crash of 2008, in that the success of businesses is coming down to their resilience. However, unlike these past events, we have no definite timeline for recovery. There is no telling whether this will be a couple of months of economic downturn or many years. Thus, associations must form strategies that take this uncertainty into account.

When building a strategy, associations must react quickly. Restructure your organization as fast as possible in order to survive. Cash is extremely important- associations are already dealing with diminishing or halted cash flow, and many will run out of money if they do not make these adjustments quickly enough.

When considering new strategies, associations should also put measures in place that will allow them to rapidly adjust based on what happens in the future. Associations should also consider the long term implications of these crises and adapt to these- for example, even once governments permit large events, how will customers react and readjust?

In addition, associations should be wary of any emotional decisions. It can be extremely difficult to quickly adjust or shift away from methods that have been used forever and been successful in the past, but innovating new solutions is the only way associations will move forward. Associations must take a step back and look from a hostile point of view. Changing times require changing strategies.

With these high levels of uncertainty, however, also come opportunities. Associations must stay aware of the changing industries and changing demands. For example, we’re seeing an opening in the certification industry and online education. Formulate a business plan that takes advantage of these new opportunities. Every association has the opportunity to rediscover their industry amidst the crisis.
<h2>New Revenue Models</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16137 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/value-copy-58@2x.png" alt="key members" width="1920" height="1030" />

This shift online is also forcing associations to rethink their revenue models. In-person events are a large driver of revenue, especially in Asia. Associations are facing the challenge of how to monetize their online communities.

When looking to monetize online events, associations must analyze the demand side of the business to determine where they can provide value and plan their supply chain according to that. After determining where they can provide this value, they must look for the source: how do you get the components in your event to create that value?

This could mean working with technology players and other service providers to bring complementing components to the product. Then, associations can operationalize this product so that members will come back and be willing to pay for it.

Associations must also consider their competition: it’s no longer just the local associations. The competition is now heightened to the global landscape and is not limited to other event organizers. Tech companies themselves are also competitors.

For example, for things like online certifications, associations may not be equipped to compete with the array of competitors. Therefore, associations need to plan and source appropriately to be able to compete. Remember that the ability to organize events doesn’t necessarily translate to the ability to organize webinars or live experience.

To combat this increased competition, associations should seek sponsorship or work alongside other industry players.
<h2><b>Membership Model</b></h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16091 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/value-copy-57@2x.png" alt="membership strategy" width="1920" height="1030" />

One trend that we are seeing amidst the coronavirus crisis is associations offering free membership. Is this something your association should be doing?

This all depends on how much of your revenue is generated from memberships. For example, associations in the United States usually generate half their revenue from membership payments, whereas associations in India generate far less from membership.

Offering free membership is a way of reaching out as an association and shows your members that you care for them. If you decide to offer it, make sure to use it your advantage and use it to grow your membership base.

If associations offer free membership without considering the financial implications for their specific associations and without utilizing it to its full advantage by generating new members, it will just burn cash. Ensure that your choice is right for your associations and aligns with your redefined value proposition.
<h2>Online Business Model</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17196 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/tips-communities-going-digital.png" alt="webinar technology" width="1200" height="644" />

Converting live events onto a virtual platform is obviously the easiest solution in the current climate. However, this should not be an ad hoc solution by any means: when converting their events, associations must take the time to truly analyze their online business model and connect with their members.

To develop an online business model, communication with customers is key. Through time, find regular touchpoints within the industry that you are focused on. After webinars, follow up and collect attendee feedback. Determine what real value you are offering through your online services. Once this is determined, <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/paid-webinar-strategies/">you can then begin to monetize</a>.

Consider the changes you need to make to your content and your staff as you make this switch. From a content perspective, there are a lot of professionals who may be very experienced in live events, but unable to convert this experience online. How can your association help and educate them to become outstanding virtual facilitators and speakers?

In terms of staff, look at the talent within your organization. Do you have the right talent for the right jobs? What’s coming next requires creating new roles and redefining old roles.

Finally, consider how you are going to program your webinar. How will you convert a three-day conference into an online event that people are interested in participating in? People have a current attention span of eight seconds, so we really need to change the dynamics of these events and program webinars like a TV show.

Use customer feedback to determine how long to make your live events and ensure that customers are staying engaged.
<h2>Going Forward</h2>
Lots of uncertainty lies ahead, but one thing is for sure. The industry will never go back to the way it was before with an overwhelmed supply of face to face events. Recovery is going to entail a better combination of face to face engagement and digital aspects. The way that this fusion looks for your association is up to you, based on your value proposition and your market.

If you're looking for a way to digitalize your organization and improve your membership experience, <a href="https://get.eventbank.com/community-engagement-solution/?utm_source=membervaluepostpandemic&amp;utm_medium=blog"><strong>Book a Demo</strong></a> today, and we'll show you how EventBank's engagement platform has been helping chambers and associations the world over with thier post-COVID 19 woes.

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17578</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-08 02:31:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-08 02:31:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[member-value-post-pandemic]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="associations"><![CDATA[Associations]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="associations-chambers"><![CDATA[Associations &amp; Chambers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="chambers"><![CDATA[chambers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="digital"><![CDATA[digital]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="membership"><![CDATA[membership]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[90]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[member value]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Providing Value to Members in a Post-Pandemic World]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[See how other associations and chambers of commerce are providing the same or even more value to their members in a post-COVID-19 world.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[61]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17596]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>What’s a Digital Business Card and How Do I Get One?</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/digital-business-cards/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 09:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[robert]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=17613</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Digital business cards are a new concept that’s been slowly advancing toward day-to-day use by leveraging smartphones that sit in every professional’s pocket these days. Its user adoption has been slow, but subtle hints at its emergence in 2020 are becoming more and more apparent. But if you’re out of the loop and not sure what a digital business card entails, we’ll break it down and answer some frequently asked questions about what they are, how they work, and how you can get one.
<h2>What is a digital business card?</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17276 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/business-carrd@2x.png" alt="webinar digital business card exchange" width="1986" height="1666" />

A digital business card is, at its core, a business card that exists online under an account you own and can log into at any time. It has all your contact information, title, company name, logo, and everything you would expect on a business card.

With a range of platforms hosting digital business cards, you can actually a few more goodies that make it more interactive and engaging for recipients, like adding optional additional info, portfolio of work, and more.

LinkedIn has, in fact, been a de-facto digital business card for professionals looking for ways to keep in touch, but its a social aspect, constant news feeds, publicity, and the fact that you can’t easily export your contacts, leads to LinkedIn being a somewhat less optimal way to digitally exchange contact info.

A digital business card should be easily exchanged, easily managed, and easily accessible.
<h2>Why use digital business cards?</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16414 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy@2x.png" alt="digital membership cards" width="1920" height="1030" />

Aside from the more green aspect of using a digital business card over a physical one, a digital business card never needs to be replenished, and it can be exchanged both in person, as well as online.

A digital business card also has the added benefit of interacting with physical business cards so that any person you might run into who doesn’t share your fondness of digital business cards can still not only hand you their card, but the card can be scanned into your database of choice. This is a feature existing in some CRMs, but with a digital business card involved, the experience can be reciprocal to your contacts.

Further, digital cards are dynamic, and can be edited any time should you change work, title, or contact info, removing the headache of ordering new cards.
<h2>How do digital business cards work?</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16516 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-3@2x.png" alt="chambers and associations" width="1920" height="1030" />

Digital business cards can come in a few different varieties, but essentially it’s a piece of content that is not public but is shareable. It emulates the information a business card would have about you, albeit with a few extras and functionality you wouldn’t normally get on a physical card.

You might find a digital business card existing on your phone, on a social media platform, a community platform, or potentially just it’s own app on your phone or desktop. The cards can then be shared with others at your whim, either through a link, QR code, or a handshake popup or notification on a centralized platform for this sort of communication (think LinkedIn notifications for requests to connect, but not publicly).

Some extra functionality can be the ability to scan physical cards so they’ve saved in your digital Rolodex, making it a lot more conscionable to tidy up your physical cards that seem to grow year on year.

This means you can share your business card digitally to contacts on webinars, through group chats, or even in-person should they hand you a physical card, completing the bridge between your digital and physical networking strategy.
<h2>Where can I get a digital business card?</h2>
[caption id="attachment_5466" align="aligncenter" width="600"]<img class="wp-image-5466 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/image-2.png" alt="Digital Membership Cards" width="600" height="600" /> <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/digital-membership-cards/">Digital Membership cards</a> were the brainchild to digital business cards in the MICE industry.[/caption]

This tech is actually still in its infancy, as we eluded to prior, social platforms like LinkedIn are already doing the job of connecting professionals but in a public manner that doesn’t include direct-contact information that makes it easier to communicate. LinkedIn Connects you, but it doesn’t glue you together.

Some platforms are attempting to release their own versions of the digital business card, and for the time being, it seems like there will be many platforms competing for the market until a leader emerges. Or, on the other side of things, it will simply be a feature that begins to standardize itself in current platforms, time will only tell.

As for where you can get a digital business card right now?

Try checking out a few like Dibiz, Haystack, Ingio, or Switchit App, however, you’ll find them somewhat lacking in the functionality that we’ve mentioned before. Some apps even require the other person you want to exchange with to have the exact same app in order to exchange. It’s not a perfect solution, but there could be some good internal uses here should you need them.

At EventBank we’ve built our communities to leverage their own internal business card exchange during events, webinars, or simply in the real &amp; digital world so that attendees and organization members can better network without getting in the way of community discussions and activities.

<b>Book a demo</b> today to learn more about how EventBank can help attendees network without distracting your community with truly digital business cards.

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17613</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-09 09:56:25]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-09 09:56:25]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[digital-business-cards]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="associations-chambers"><![CDATA[Associations &amp; Chambers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="business-cards"><![CDATA[business cards]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="event-management"><![CDATA[Event Management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="members"><![CDATA[members]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="networking"><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[What’s a Digital Business Card and How Do I Get One?]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Digital business cards are a growing trend among internal communities because it's non-intrusive, easy to manage, and completel the online-offline journey.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17618]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>21 Webinar Survey Questions to Ask Before, During, and After</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/webinar-survey-questions/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 06:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carl]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=17923</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Surveys are an important aspect when it comes to webinars and events because it provides feedback and information from your audience members you may not be able to receive any other way. Surveys can assist in an objective view of your webinars and see the improvements you can make. This creates a higher accuracy than relying on gut feeling. It can also help you with the future targeting of audiences by looking at target populations and analyzing the data. <b>In short, surveys can help you improve the quality and the customer perceived value of your webinars and events.</b>
<h3>Skip To</h3>
<strong><a href="#before">Before</a></strong>
<strong><a href="#during">During</a></strong>
<strong><a href="#after">After</a></strong>
<h2>Tips for Designing a Webinar Survey</h2>
<img class="alignnone wp-image-17304 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/eventbank-webinars-network.png" alt="webinar networking" width="1200" height="644" />

When you send your survey out, you want to have as many participants respond to the survey as possible. This ensures that you get the most feedback from the participants which can be used to improve your webinar and also lowers the possibility of skewed results. These tips below can ensure that more people follow through with your survey and not immediately be deterred when they open the form.
<h3>Start with the Easy Questions</h3>
When designing your webinar survey, start with the easy questions first. The easy questions can consist of true/false, or multiple-choice questions. Starting with the easier questions allows the participant to be more willing to start filling out the survey because of the perceived belief that it would be a quick survey, and not take up a lot of their time. And as the survey goes on, you put your open-ended questions near the end. This ensures the participants will be more willing to complete your survey because they have already invested their time in it.
<h3>Not too Long</h3>
Your survey should never be too long because a long survey will deter your participants from filling out the survey and lower the quality of your survey answers. A survey that takes 20 mins or more to complete will start having less thoughtful and lower quality responses. In order to have your participants fill out a survey with good information, make sure that your survey takes less than 15-20 minutes to complete.
<h3>Limit the Choices</h3>
When writing a closed-ended question, ensure that you do not have too many decisions for your participants to choose from. More choices often lead to worse user experiences. In order to limit create a good user experience, limit the choices. But if there are many choices needed, you can always put an “other” option where your participant can fill out their choice.
<h2 id="before">Pre-Webinar Questions</h2>
<img class="alignnone wp-image-17341 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/emails-blog@2x.png" alt="webinar invite email examples" width="2400" height="1288" />

Pre-Webinar questions are a good way to gauge the interest of the audience for your webinar and it can help with some aspects of the planning process. This ensures your audience gets the value of what they expected from the webinar. In addition, this early engagement with the audience members before your webinar will also encourage them to attend the webinar when the day comes.
<h3>1. Which speakers are you excited about?</h3>
This question can help you understand who the webinar audiences want to see. This can assist in your planning by allowing that speaker to have more time sharing their ideas and also have them speak at more of your webinars to increase the number of paying audience members.
<h3>2. Have you attended our events or webinars before?</h3>
This question illustrates the number of audience members that are returning customers. This shows your customer retention rate. Loyal audience members prove that you are hitting the right topics for your target audience.
<h3>3. How did you hear about this webinar?</h3>
Finding out where audience members heard about your events can help you decide on what platforms to market your webinars. Increased promotion on these platforms can help you with an uptick in sales for your webinar.
<h3>4. Why did you choose to attend this webinar?</h3>
This can help you figure out what aspects of the webinar are the most attractive to audience members. You could be picking all the right topics that audience members are currently interested in, or your audience members could be really pleased with your speakers. Figuring out what you are doing right can help you continue doing it right.
<h3>5. What device are you planning on using?</h3>
If different audience members are planning on using different devices, such as a mobile device, your webinar platform needs to be able to support that. A webinar platform that can support all the devices that your audience members are using will not deter any audience member from any future webinars.
<h3>6. Was there any information that was hard to find?</h3>
Some information that the audience member may want or need may not be readily available for them before the webinar. Asking this question can ensure all the necessary information was provided to the audience member ahead of time.
<h2 id="during">During Webinar Questions</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16882 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-COVID@2x.png" alt="webinar tips" width="1920" height="1030" />
<h3>7. Are there any tech issues you are experiencing?</h3>
Tech issues can occur during your webinars and they could ruin an audience member’s experience of your webinar. Asking this question allows some audience members to bring up an issue that the tech team can try to fix it for them. You could have a separate survey box that is consistently open so they can ask for help whenever needed.
<h3>8. Are there any things you would like the speakers to elaborate on?</h3>
This survey question can be sent out through the webinar platform near the end of the webinar. This ensures that the audience members do get the information they joined the webinar for. This creates value for your audience members and incentivizes them to become repeat customers
<h3>9. Are there any questions?</h3>
This is always an important question to ask that can be on a survey on your platform. Being an open-ended question the audience members can ask any question to the topics they are confused about. Audience members who have their questions cleared up leave with higher satisfaction.
<h2 id="after">Post-Webinar Questions</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16810 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-phone@2x.png" alt="mobile notifications" width="2400" height="1288" />

Post webinar questions can arguably be the most important questions you ask. When you send out your post-webinar survey, you get feedback on the delivery of your webinar, which is the product/service that your audience members paid for. All feedback negative or positive can help improve your webinars to keep the most amount of recurring customers.
<h3>10. How would you rate the webinar?</h3>
This is a simple question that gets straight to the point with your audience members. This question should be asked in a scaled format and allows you to gather how much your audience enjoyed your webinar. If they enjoyed it, you are doing something right. If they did not enjoy it, you need to figure out what's wrong and change it before you lose all your audience members.
<h3>11. How would you rate the speakers?</h3>
The speakers are an integral part of your webinars. Amazing speakers can be a great benefit to your webinars. When your recurring audience members enjoy the speakers that are a part of your webinars, it keeps them as recurring customers and improves the overall value of your webinar.
<h3>12. How would you rate the technology?</h3>
The technological aspect of webinars is one of the most important things to consider. Since everything needs to be done online on computers, the technology has to work for all your audience members. If you could get feedback on how to improve aspects of your tech, it would improve your audience member’s experiences.
<h3>13. Were your expectations met?</h3>
Going into a webinar, your audience members will have an internal expectation of the quality and the value that they are predicting they would get out of the webinar. Of course, you would want to meet the expectation at the least. But knowing whether or not audience members were impressed by the webinar or were disappointed can prove invaluable data for you and the future of your webinars.
<h3>14. How satisfied are you with the networking tools?</h3>
Networking is important for may of your audience members who join your webinars. You must provide good networking tools to create value for your audience members. If the tools are up-to-par, you would be creating value not only on the information shared on your webinar but also the connections they make attending it.
<h3>15. Would you contact someone you networked within the webinar?</h3>
The next step of good networking tools is that the audience members contact the people they networked with during the webinar. If they are planning on contacting the people they networked with, they are getting an additional value, which is good for the perception of your webinar
<h3>16. Has your perception of the company improved through the webinar?</h3>
Having your audience members have a more positive perception of your company can increase sales. And if your webinar helps drive revenue from ticket sales as well as increases the perception of your company, you are killing two birds with one stone!
<h3>17. What were your favorite/least favorite moments in the webinar?</h3>
This helps you identify the driving factors on why an audience member may become a recurring audience member or not. Focusing on the positive aspects and ensuring that they do not falter while improving the negative aspects will improve your webinar overall.
<h3>18. Did you find the platform easy to use?</h3>
An easy to use platform for a webinar is crucial for repeat audience members. Because of a gentle learning curve, more people will be able to join the webinar and be more willing to come back because it does not require difficult planning on their end.
<h3>19. How likely would you recommend this webinar to a friend?</h3>
If your audience members enjoy your webinars and recommend your webinar to a friend, it can drive ticket sales. This can also increase the number of recurring audience members you have.
<h3>20. Will you join our next event?</h3>
This is a straightforward question that can help you figure out who would become a recurring customer or not. High numbers mean that you have hosted a successful webinar, low numbers mean that there are improvements to be made.
<h3>21. Any improvements that can be made to the webinar?</h3>
There are always improvements to be made to your webinar to create more customer value. Some of these improvements may not be highlighted by your other survey questions, so make sure this is an open-ended question, and that your audience members can explain and give their feedback.
<h2>Value of Information</h2>
Information about your webinar from your audience is of immense value. Always remember that you are trying to <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/successful-webinar-strategies/">create value</a> for them so they will keep attending your webinars. Take their feedback and use it to build even better webinars in the future, and you're sure to see your online events skyrocket in popularity and value.

Are you looking to find ways to not only provide value through surveys, but smarter ways to deploy surveys to your webinar or in-person event audiences? <a href="https://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=webinarsurveys"><strong>Book a demo</strong></a> with EventBank today, and we'll show you how our platform has been helping thousands of customers with their digital engagement.

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17923</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-15 06:32:46]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-15 06:32:46]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[webinar-survey-questions]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="guide"><![CDATA[guide]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="surveys"><![CDATA[surveys]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="webinars"><![CDATA[webinars]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[51]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[21 Webinar Survey Questions to Ask Before, During, and After]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[90]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[41]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[21 Webinar Survey Questions you should ask your audience Before, During, and After your event so you can learn and build better webinars in the future.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17934]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[webinar survey questions]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Hybrid-Webinar Events: Combining Your Online and Offline Attendees</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/hybrid-webinars/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 08:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[robert]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18068</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Have you ever heard of a webinar hybrid event? Starting from the beginning, during Covid-19, businesses switch their entire events strategy to almost entirely online events and webinars.

This obviously provides the opportunity of still hosting events at a time when physical events are not possible, but a lot is left to be desired when it comes to being on a webinar, mainly engagement, networking, and ticketing. (Though we do have a guide that helps you get around these obstacles.)

But now as we see cities opening up, we’re in a weird limbo of being able to go out to meetings and conferences again but just locally, as we’re still unable to travel to most other areas to attend far distance events. This is where a hybrid webinar-conference might start to make sense.
<h2>What’s a Hybrid Webinar?</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17365 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sem-webinars@2x-1.png" alt="webinar speaker" width="1920" height="1030" />

<b>A webinar hybrid is a physical in-person event or series of in-person events that have been integrated seamlessly with an online audience</b> who can listen to speakers, engage with activities, and network with attendees both online and offline.

A hybridized event is more than just a live stream of an event to an online audience, it’s an event that’s run on a platform that benefits both attendees on the event floor and those watching online by providing a digital space for the two audiences to interact, while still attending the same content.

Some hybrid events even use this aspect to host <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/event-spaces-going-digital/">multiple in-person events across the world</a> in different locations, so the same event can take place in different cities simultaneously, while still having each audience come together as a whole digital audience online
<h2>Examples of Hybrid Webinars</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16951 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-webinars@2x.png" alt="digital meeting" width="1920" height="1030" />

Imagine you’re at an event and you’re in the crowd watching the panel discussion for instance. There's 40 something people in the room, but there could be hundreds more watching from online.

After the event, you want to talk and network with your fellow attendees, so talk to some folks in the room, but what about those hundreds of other viewers from the internet?

Just flip out your phone and just like that, you can open an app that gets you in touch with communities, chat rooms, business card exchanges, Q&amp;A forums, and more so that you can engage and network with both online and offline audiences.

On the reverse side, if you’re not able to travel for any reason, but you still want to attend a popular conference out of the country, simply log into the event online and you’ll be tuned into the event’s speakers, panels, shows, etc.

But now, with a hybridized event, you’re not just tuned into the event’s content, you’re also on an engaging platform that is helping you communicate with other attendees who are online, and those that are on the floor. Discuss in live chats for each session of the event, submit live polls according to event types, exchange digital business cards, and more.
<h2>Launching a Hybrid Event</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16672 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/value-copy-58@1x.png" alt="conference networking tips" width="1200" height="644" />

Launching a hybrid event is a semi-complex situation, but most platforms these days that you’re used to using to handle your event management needs are similar in a lot of respects.
<h3>What you’re used to</h3>
Some things you may be familiar with in a hybrid webinar platform are some of the basics that don’t disappear suddenly because you’re hybridizing your event.

You’ll need a <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/digital-transformation-attendee-experience/"><b>contact management system</b></a>, or<b> CRM</b>, an <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/webinar-invite-email-examples/"><b>email marketing tool</b></a>, an <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/event-website-templates/"><b>event website or webpage</b></a>, and a <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/paid-webinar-strategies/"><b>ticketing interface</b></a> for attendees to register and optionally purchase tickets.

Nothing about these needs has changed for any reason when concerning a hybrid event, and more or less you’ve likely used them before. If not, there’s plenty of documentation that comes with most basic event management software that can explain it for you.

In a nutshell, the pre-event preparation is going to be similar with some slight deviance in wording, including making it clear in your promotional materials and website that the event is both for in-person attendees and viewers online.

The difficult part is accurately explaining that online attendees can engage with attendees on the event floor, and this wording concern is still a learning curve for first-time hybrid event organizers.
<h3>What you’re not used to</h3>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-15108 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-13@2x.png" alt="event data collection" width="1920" height="1030" />

However, what you may not be used to when running a hybridized webinar, is the level of digital interface needed to seamlessly engage both online and offline audiences.

This includes properly preparing any speakers, panelists, or hosts with the running of the show and how the in-person show is inexorably intertwined with the online audience, and that their online viewers are just as interactive with the event itself as the people on the show floor.

For instance, the first thing needed to be tackled is the platform itself, and understanding what a hybrid platform does to make these engagements happen.

This could be a <b>live chat room</b>, a <b>live <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/successful-webinar-strategies/">stream/webinar module</a></b>, <b> live polling, <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/digital-business-cards/">digital business card exchanging</a>, <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/attendee-messaging/">direct messaging</a>, </b>and more<b>. </b>

These types of engagement mediums are probably something not implemented in typical physical events, while some may be present in webinars.

It’s about having a mindset that these engagements are optional, but also encourage that they are used so that both online and offline audiences can benefit.

Remember that a lot of the reason people want to attend events is for the networking aspect, and by completing the bridge between the online and offline audience, you’ve now provided an astounding amount of value to your hybrid event.

You’ve bridged gaps that have existed for years, and you’ve removed a lot of cons for both event types by doing so while keeping all the pros.

If you’re interested in learning more about how to hybridize your events and webinars or otherwise create engaging events and webinars, <strong><a href="https://get.eventbank.com/webinar-solution/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=hybridwebinars">contact us</a></strong> today and we’ll show you how to bring your events to life with our all in one engagement platform.

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18068</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-19 08:41:05]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-19 08:41:05]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hybrid-webinars]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="event-management"><![CDATA[Event Management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="technology"><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="webinars"><![CDATA[webinars]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Hybrid-Webinar Events: Combining Your Online and Offline Attendees]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Hybrid webinar events are a great way to bridge the gap between your online audience of a webinar, and your offline audience at an in-person event.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[hybrid webinars]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18082]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>7 Survey Best Practices for Events and Webinars</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/survey-events-webinars/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 07:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[robert]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18105</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[We always like to tout the effectiveness of attendee tracking, analytics, and personalization for the purpose of gauging event and webinar success, but at the end of the day hearing feedback from the attendees themselves will always trump any analytics.

However, you <i>can</i> mess up how you deliver a survey by not following some best practices like:

<a href="#platform">Choosing a Decent Survey Platform</a>
<a href="#questions">Crafting Short and Sweet Questions</a>
<a href="#purpose">Explain the Survey’s Purpose</a>
<a href="#completion">Never Require 100% Completion</a>
<a href="#proritize">Prioritize Important Questions First</a>
<a href="#time">Mention the Estimated Completion Time</a>
<a href="#results">Share the Results</a>
<h2 id="platform">1. Choosing a Decent Survey Platform</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17277 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/webinar-solution-eventbank@2x.png" alt="webinar management software" width="1367" height="1080" />

Surveys aren’t done on paper anymore, events and webinars these days can get into the thousands of attendees, and going digital with survey deliver make it easier to deal with all the responses.

This however makes it less engaging, as a lot of attendees feel a need to complete a paper-form survey handed to them during an event than if it just arrived in an email in their inbox.

So from the get-go, dealing with digital surveys will take some tact to make them engaging so you can maximize their effectiveness. It also goes without saying that webinars are solely digital surveys anyways.

Choosing an effective survey platform or provider is entirely up to how you deal with your digital attendee engagement, and likely that revolves around using a CRM or <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/best-event-management-software/">event management software</a>.

There is notable software for specializing in surveys out there like SurveyMonkey, but it’s important to make sure you’re automatically updating attendee profiles in your CRM automatically with responses, and for that, please read their integrations page for more details.

For a more embedded experience, event management platforms are offering surveys built into their apps or even their email marketing platforms. These are native, internal integrations that likely work much better and remove an unnecessary cost from the software side of things.

As for what to look for in a survey tool, the only real importance is how much editing power you have over the tool and how that data is used once collected.

Most tools do a good job of this as survey tools have become more standardized over time, but still, make sure you have some available admin rights in order to follow throw with more of our advice coming up in this article, like for instance, the ability to give Skip Logic to survey questions.
<h2 id="questions">2. Crafting Short and Sweet Questions</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-10958 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/blog-post-43-copy@2x.png" alt="event room layouts" width="1920" height="1030" />

Short and sweet questions easy to answer, and give probably the same information as to what you’re looking for.

A rookie mistake when surveying anyone is that you want them to be ultra detailed with their answers and get as much feedback as possible from one subject. It’s not possible, and frankly it just scares people away from starting it.

Your questions should be directly asking what you’re looking to improve. Do you just want a score of 1 to 10 how good was the event or webinar they just attended? Simply ask that.

You can also extend these qualitative or multi-choice questions a bit longer, maybe towards 5-10 questions if they’re all equally short and simple too. Some people seem to have an obsession with completing fill-in questions, so they may actually complete it in full.

No need to ask them to write down their experience, it’s just not necessary, but by all means, leave a comments section at the end anyways for their optional feedback.

However, if you need constructive feedback, now is the time to ask one or two open-ended questions that are specific to what you feel you can tackle coming up.

Asking how the A/V set up was when you have no budget for new A/V equipment is likely the wrong question since it’s not something actionable. So make sure when you ask constructive questions, they're questions with whom’s answers can be acted upon directly.
<h2 id="purpose">3. Explain the Survey’s Purpose</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16470 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-2@2x-2.png" alt="marketing trends in 2020" width="1920" height="1030" />

Make sure in your delivery or promotion of the survey after your event, that you explain the purpose of the survey.

Everyone knows what a survey is, but if you can explain why you’re surveying them and what that survey may lead to, it would actually propel some individuals to complete the survey.

We wish we had more tips for you, but this is as simple as it gets, add a message in your delivery that shows your intent of the survey and what it may lead to.

For instance if you’re looking to improve speaker quality at events and webinars you host in the future, maybe you should just say that in your survey delivery email: “Your answers will help us improve the quality of speaker selection in the future.”.
<h2 id="completion">4. Never Require 100% Completion</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16810 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-phone@2x.png" alt="mobile notifications" width="2400" height="1288" />

In any survey, never require a single question. Yes, you may get bogus feedback, missing data, and so on, but missing data is better than no data. Some questions may come off as too uncomfortable, or maybe they just don’t have feedback or anything to say.

Making it non-compulsive to complete every single question will lead to more actual submissions of feedback, and overall you’ll have more data to use, even if every delivery was not 100 percent complete.

When analytically looking at this data though, it’s important that if you have qualitative questions, do not divide your percentage of completion by total number of survey submissions, but by submissions that have answered that question and not skipped it like others may have.
<h2 id="prioritize">5. Prioritize Important Questions First</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16558 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-5@2x.png" alt="content prioritization" width="1920" height="1030" />

Piggybacking off our advice on never requiring 100% completion of a survey, we still want you to get the pertinent feedback that’s important for you, and so our advice is to make sure that the first questions in your survey are ordered from most important to least important.

Doing so will ensure the of those who do attempt to complete, or mostly complete, a survey will deliver your most valued feedback first.
<h2 id="time">6. Mention the Estimated Completion Time</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16965 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/blog-young-professionals@2x.png" alt="young professionals" width="1920" height="1030" />

In the delivery of your survey, mention either how many questions the survey is, the estimated time of completion, or both.

It’s a simple gesture that helps your recipients better gauge their time-cost of completing the survey and likely will entice more people to complete because it’s not as long as they first though.

Likely because you followed our advice on short and sweet questions, right? ;)
<h2 id="results">7. Share the Results</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16771 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/eventbank-blog@2x.png" alt="in person event seminars" width="1920" height="1030" />

Finally, after the survey period is over, be sure to share the results of the survey with those that completed the survey.

You can even use this aspect to promote users to finish the survey when you deliver it. By saying only those that complete the survey will receive the results, you’ve added some exclusivity to the recipients and likely incentivized the curious ones to complete the survey.

Be sure that when sending the survey results, you understand the survey feedback type. If it was a simple multi-choice or qualitative questionnaire, then you can probably just deliver them directly as-is compiled into a nice graph or chart.

However, a questionnaire with more personalized feedback might need to be collected, reviewed, and then summarized for recipients of the results. Make sure it shows not only a summary of the major feedback but also it’s a great time to either reinforce or otherwise double down on what action you’ll take to improve future events based on their feedback.

If you’re looking for a way to not only deliver actionable surveys to your audience or members, but also a way that tracks user experience, their survey answers, and actions taken, consider <a href="https://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=surveybestpractices"><b>booking a demo</b></a> with EventBank and we’ll show you how our engagement software solution can deliver.

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18105</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-24 07:02:15]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-24 07:02:15]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[survey-events-webinars]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="surveys"><![CDATA[surveys]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="webinars"><![CDATA[webinars]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[41]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[survey best practices]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7 Survey Best Practices for Events and Webinars]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7 survey best practices you can use for your next event or webinar that can help you take more action and improve your future events and succeed!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[63]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18112]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Ultimate Webinar Sponsorship Guide</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/webinar-sponsorship-guide/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 10:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[robert]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18123</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[With the COVID-19 pandemic severely limiting events and opportunities to host large scale events, many companies are now shifting their gears to hosting online webinars and other virtual events.

Some companies are offering their webinars for free but many other companies are utilizing <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/paid-webinar-strategies/">paid webinars</a> to boost value and make some profit on their webinars with the use of webinar management software that adds more engagement to the typical webinar platform like ticketing, account log-ins, communities, <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/survey-events-webinars/">live polling</a>, <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/digital-business-cards/">virtual business card exchanging</a>, and more.

These companies are usually charging their audience members for tickets but that puts all the cost of the webinars on your audience members, which could be limiting.

It could lessen the number of audience members that <strong>may not be able or be willing to pay for your webinars, but are still very much engaged with your brand</strong>.

In addition, it could limit the amount you can charge each audience member to ensure that the audience members see that the value from participation is much higher than the price of the webinar.

Sponsorships are another means to generate revenue without putting all the cost on your audience members and also create some partnerships with other companies that could benefit from sponsoring your webinars, the long term benefits are without understatement.

But first, ask yourself this:
<h2>Are Sponsorships Valuable to You?</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17548 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/june-edm@2x.png" alt="webinar value" width="1920" height="1030" />

Sponsorships on Webinars, not unlike events, can be valuable to you. Not too many reasons would spring to mind when considering Sponsorships for webinars.

You don’t need to rent out a physical space, catering is not needed, audiences who need to travel, and so on, however, sponsorships still can bring monetary aid as well as credibility to your webinars. Sometimes, the sponsorship leading to having the right logo on promotional materials is enough already.
<h3>Budget</h3>
Sponsorships can help with your budget as you may be able to generate more revenue than you could have without them.

If you opt-in for a ticket based audience registration as well as sponsoring companies, you would be maximizing the revenue generated from your webinars.

However, if you could use your sponsorship to lower the ticket prices for your audience members, then you could increase the value of the webinar for them by making it more affordable.

This can lead to larger webinar audiences which can increase your sponsors and your revenue, creating a positive feedback loop.
<h3>Credibility</h3>
Sponsorships by companies that are well known can help you improve the credibility of your webinars.

With all the webinars popping up during these times, people will be more likely to trust webinars that are sponsored by a credible company. This would increase your credibility as well as registrations for your event.
<h3>Beware of Shark-Sponsors</h3>
Be wary of sponsors that seek to leverage your webinar for their own benefit by flaunting the rules, claiming credit, or otherwise disrupting the event in a means to their benefit only.

It may seem strange, but some sponsors out there will use their large brand image to disrupt entire events and webinars in both minor or major ways, from claiming credit or otherwise marketing the event as if it was their own, giving away free tickets to registrants that buy their products, and so on.
<h2>How to Find Sponsors</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16951 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-webinars@2x.png" alt="digital meeting" width="1920" height="1030" />

There are steps that you need to follow before you can attain the right sponsors for your webinar. The first thing needed is to find the right sponsors for your event.

Additionally, you need to convince the sponsors that they are the right sponsor for your event and that they would be getting value from sponsoring your event as well.
<h3>Transfer Your Event Sponsors</h3>
This one is quite easy. If you ran events with sponsors in the past, simply reach out to them and see if they'd be interested in sponsoring your online events as well. Webinars have come a long way, and sponsorship of webinars is becoming just as fruitful as in-person events, thanks to leaps in<a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/successful-webinar-strategies/"> technology making engagement easier online</a>.
<h3>Getting The Right Sponsors</h3>
Getting the right sponsors for your webinars is an important consideration to make when looking for webinar sponsors.

The wrong sponsors can hinder your progress and could convey a message that was not your attention and attract the wrong audience members.

The right sponsors can help you target your audience a little bit better, and attract positive media attention as well as larger amounts of audience members.
<h3>Know Your Webinar</h3>
Knowing your webinar topic and target audiences can help you immensely in finding the right sponsors for your webinar.

This can help you find the potential sponsors you would be happy partnering with. Knowing all the information about your webinar can also help you answer questions to the sponsors you reach out to.

Many sponsors will have a myriad of questions to figure out if they believe that sponsoring your event is a good fit for them.

Having the information readily available can convey a higher sense of professionalism.
<h3>Target Your Audience</h3>
Knowing your target audience is an important step to any webinar, it allows you to cater to your topic and your presentation to your audience. But knowing what companies your target audiences frequent or have a positive view of can help you pick the right sponsors for your webinars.

Picking these sponsors can help you drive higher attendance and registration for your webinars from your target audience.
<h2>Proving ROI</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-15478 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/value-copy-18@2x-1.png" alt="association revenue ideas" width="2400" height="1288" />

Providing ROI on previous sponsors for your webinars can be beneficial in convincing new sponsors to become new sponsors of your webinars.

These numbers and data provide hard facts for your new potential sponsors to analyze and understand the benefits of sponsoring your events.
<h3>Webinar Data</h3>
Providing data on the webinar would be a beneficial asset to you and your sponsor because it gives them quantitative data to understand the benefits to sponsoring your webinar. Potential metrics to share with your webinar sponsors are:
<ul>
 	<li>The number of audience members on your previous webinar.</li>
 	<li>The number of leads that each sponsor received in your previous webinar.</li>
 	<li>The number of return audience members in your previous webinars</li>
</ul>
<h3>Demographics</h3>
Demographics can help a sponsor decide if sponsoring your event is the right fit for them. If the audience members to your webinars are not in the target market they would be less likely to invest in sponsoring your event.

However, with the target market matching the audience in your webinars, it becomes a worthy investment for your sponsors and they may be more willing to sponsor your webinar.
<h3>Testimonials/Survey</h3>
Testimonials and survey responses from audience members also give another layer of depth for qualitative data for your potential sponsors to consider.

The surveys and audience members' testimonials can create an additional layer to the ROI you can provide to the sponsors to convince them that your webinar is the right choice for them to sponsor.
<h2>Sponsorship Packages</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16809 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-mobile@2x.png" alt="audience engagement" width="1920" height="1030" />

When asking for sponsors for your webinars, you should create different packages for different sponsors. This tiered sponsorship can help you differentiate different sponsors by giving different benefits.

The more expensive tiers can come with direct marketing and speaking opportunities from the sponsors as well as banner ads during the webinar.

The lower tiers can have a shout-out at the beginning or end of the webinar.

However, you must make it clear the prices and the benefits of each tier. You would not want your sponsors and you to have a misunderstanding because that can destroy relationships with your sponsors and destroy your reputation for other sponsors.

In addition, sponsors will only buy your packages if they are clear on what they receive when they purchase the package.

Ensure your package descriptions are clear on what the benefits and prices are.

Sponsorships for events are a common practice but because of the COVID-19 pandemic, events are no longer as widespread.

As webinars are on the rise, sponsorships on webinars will be the next trend.

Get ahead of the curve and start setting up sponsorship packages for your webinars, as these can benefit you, your sponsor, and even your audience members.

If you’re looking run great webinars that attract sponsors to you, consider <a href="https://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=surveybestpractices"><b>booking a demo</b></a> with EventBank and we’ll show you how our engagement software solution can deliver a webinar experience like never before.
<p style="text-align: center;">Or submit the form below.</p>
[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18123</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-06-29 10:12:09]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-06-29 10:12:09]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[webinar-sponsorship-guide]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="event-management"><![CDATA[Event Management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="sponsors"><![CDATA[sponsors]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="webinars"><![CDATA[webinars]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[See how you can get sponsors for your webinars with this guide on how you can outreach and entice sponsors for virtual events and webinars.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18418]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>11 Simple Steps to Start Your Own Webinar for Newbies</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/simple-webinar-tutorial/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 08:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carl]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18493</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>How to Start Your Own Webinar</h1>
Ever since the COVID-19 pandemic started, the word <b>webinar</b> has been popping up all over the internet. Blog posts about webinars are popping up as well as many companies or people starting their own webinars. But what is a webinar?
<h3 id="top">Quick Reads</h3>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 24px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 50%; height: 24px;"><a href="#topic">Decide on Your Topic</a>
<a href="#format">Decide on Webinar Format</a>
<a href="#team">Assemble Your Team</a>
<a href="#tech">Figure Out Your Tech</a>
<a href="#pricing">Decide on Pricing Structure</a>
<a href="#promote">Promote Your Webinar</a></td>
<td style="width: 50%; height: 24px;"><a href="#date">Date and Time</a>
<a href="#practice">Practice Makes Perfect</a>
<a href="#present">Present Your Webinar</a>
<a href="#follow">Follow Up with Your Audience Members</a>
<a href="#consistent">Be Consistent</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>What is a Webinar?</h3>
A webinar in the simplest terms is a seminar conducted over the internet. It usually consists of a speaker or a group of speakers presenting on a topic to a large group of audience members who submit questions and respond to polls, as well as, interact with each other.
<h3>Why Should You Host a Webinar?</h3>
Webinars are a good way for you and your company to be seen as an expert in your field as well as delivering your value by making sales indirectly.

You can also have a large international audience without needing to rent a large space to accommodate all the people. Overall, it brings a lot of value for you without needing any or many investments put into it.
<h2 id="topic">1. Decide on Your Topic</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17196 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/tips-communities-going-digital.png" alt="webinar technology" width="1200" height="644" />

Deciding your topic is an important step in starting your webinar. Without a topic, you have no webinar to present! When picking a topic you should pick something that you are knowledgeable about in order to share your opinions and ideas to a diverse audience.

People join webinars based on topics that they either are interested in or like to learn more about. Ensure that your topic, no matter how broad or specific, is one that you can speak about as well as answer questions about it.
<h3>Amazing Slide Deck</h3>
Having an amazing slide deck to present while hosting your webinar is always an added bonus that can add value to your audience members. Including a slide deck gives the audience something to read while you present, it is an added visual for your audience.

Ensure that this slide deck is amazing because bad slide decks will bore your audience members and deter them from being repeat consumers, but an interesting slide deck can keep audience members hooked and attentive during your webinar.
<h3>Know Your Audience</h3>
Knowing your audience members and your target audience is always an important consideration to make when picking your topic. You need to pick a topic that will be interesting to your target audience because not doing so can have you presenting to an audience that you have not expected to attend.

Keep your target audience in mind when picking your topics to ensure you have reached the market you desired.
<h2 id="format">2. Decide on Webinar Format</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16882" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-COVID@2x.png" alt="webinar tips" width="1920" height="1030" />

There are many different formats of webinars currently being produced on the internet. Picking the right format for your topic would be beneficial for your audience members to retain the information as well as enjoy your webinar to the fullest.
<h3>Single Presenter</h3>
A single presenter webinar format would present, create, and share the ideas she or he has when presenting the webinar. The speaker would be likely to be knowledgeable about the topic they are speaking about and also direct the questions audience members may have.

This type of webinar would be beneficial when informing your audience members about a topic or instructing the audience on a specific skill.
<h3>Panel Discussion</h3>
A panel discussion comes in handy when you have a group of experts with similar or differing opinions on a single topic that can express their views.

In these webinars, you would likely be a moderator for the panel and direct them to stay on topic and guide them towards the direction you want your webinar to progress. A panel discussion would be useful to collect differing views of a current topic and allow the audience members to side with what opinions they believe to be noteworthy.
<h3>Q &amp; A</h3>
The Q&amp;A format can be integrated into any of the above formats by ensuring there is a chatbox that audience members may be able to ask questions to the presenter or the panel.

But a focused Q&amp;A format may be an advantageous method to ensure all questions that audience members may have about your company or your webinar can be answered
<h2 id="team">3. Assemble Your Team</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16516" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-3@2x.png" alt="chambers and associations" width="1920" height="1030" />

Assembling the right team for your webinar can bring multiple positive aspects that can improve the quality of your webinar. Ensure that you have team members understand the topic, but also have team members that understand the technology hosting your webinars.

This ensures that the webinars are presented well and the tech issues are smoothed out before the hosting of the webinar.
<h3>Trained Presenters</h3>
Trained presenters are key when hosting your webinar. Trained presenters represent the face of your webinar, even with an amazing slide deck, a less than professional presenter will lower the perceived quality of your webinars.

You need to ensure that the presenters are apt at dealing with technical issues and able to transition smoothly between the technical issues and the webinar. In addition, your presenters need to understand the topic at hand to present it confidently and accurately.
<h3>On-Site IT Crew</h3>
An on-site IT crew can help with issues that can be encountered during the webinar. Audience members that have issues can ask the IT crew how to resolve their issues.

This assistance can ensure audience members can have their issues resolved in a timely manner and can continue to participate in the webinar.
<h2 id="Tech">4. Figure Out Your Tech</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17119" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/eventbank-social-wall-blog@2x-1.png" alt="community wall" width="1920" height="1030" />

Technology is the window from you to your audience members when it comes to your webinar. This means that your technology needs to be flawless even before you present your first webinar.

With flawless tech, your webinar will create a sense of professionalism that an iffy technological solution could not.
<h3>Solid Platform</h3>
Finding a platform to host your webinar that is solid and tested is a lot more cost-efficient and time-efficient compared to developing your own platform. Find a platform that suits your needs and that is within your budget.

Ensure that the platform has been well tested so you may not encounter unwanted bugs when presenting your webinars. There are many different platforms out there, but pick the one that is most suitable for you.
<h3>Accessibility</h3>
Picking an accessible platform is also important for hosting your webinar. You should pick a popular platform that many others may already have downloaded on their devices. This lowers the barrier of entry to your webinars because people tend to not enjoy installing new software onto their devices.

Moreover, ensure that your platform is accessible not only by personal computers but also by mobile devices. 25% of people sign into webinars on their mobile devices, so by not having any mobile device integration, you are segmenting out that audience group.
<h3>External Webcam and Microphone</h3>
Many of today’s computers come with webcams that are of reasonable quality, but a higher quality external camera is beneficial when presenting your webinars so you will come in a crisper, higher definition image.

Paired with this, you would need a microphone that is higher quality than your laptop microphone to ensure that your audience members can hear you clearly. These two pieces of equipment are important because they are the direct communicative link that you would have with your audience members.
<h2 id="Pricing">5. Decide on Pricing Structure</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17382" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/money-webinars@2x.png" alt="paid webinars" width="1920" height="1030" />

Your pricing structure for your webinar can either be free or priced so that you have a chance to make revenue from your webinars.

But whichever course of actions you decide on, ensure that the price matches or is lower than the audience perceived value of the webinar. If you have the price higher than the audience perceived value, they may be more unlikely to pay for tickets to your webinar.
<h3>Tickets</h3>
A way to charge for your webinars is to sell individual tickets to audience members as you would to a regular seminar. The cost of the webinar then would fully rest on your audience and the price needs to match or be lower than the perceived value of your webinar.

Ensure the price is fair for your audience members otherwise you may have no audience members purchasing tickets to your webinar.
<h3>Sponsorship</h3>
Sponsorships can also help you create revenue when it comes to your webinars. Find sponsors that line up with your target market to not only promote your webinar to reach larger audiences but also lower the ticket price or create a free webinar for your audience members.

This method ensures that you can still be creating revenue for your webinars while charging your audience members lower ticket fees or no ticket fees at all.
<h2 id="Promote">6. Promote Your Webinar</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16470" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-2@2x-2.png" alt="marketing trends in 2020" width="1920" height="1030" />

Promotions are an important step to not overlook because, without good promotions, potential audience members may not know about your webinar.
<h3>Social Media</h3>
Promotions on social media is a common way to promote something to a wide following. If you already have a social media account for your business, your target audience will be following your accounts.

This ensures that promoting on your social media accounts can inform your audience members of your webinar, to entice them to purchase a ticket and join your webinar.
<h3>Email Promotions</h3>
Email promotions can be very useful when spreading the word about your webinars because it will arrive in your potential audience member’s inboxes.

If you already have a pre-existing email list for your company, and email campaign will be useful to spread the information about your webinar to audience members that are already interested in the product or service that you offer.

This makes them have a higher probability to be interested in your webinar topic and purchase tickets to it.
<h3>Discounts</h3>
Different discounts on the price of your webinar tickets are important to drive more sales of tickets. Early bird discounts are a good way of getting in tickets sales early as well as incentivizing your potential audience members to purchase your tickets.

The lower price earlier on can create more value for your audience members to convince them to buy your webinar tickets.
<h2 id="Date">7. Date and Time</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17341" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/emails-blog@2x.png" alt="webinar invite email examples" width="2400" height="1288" />

Deciding the date and time of your webinars is important not for you but also for your audience members. A time that is not accessible for your audience members to join your webinar can deter many potential, interested audience members from purchasing a ticket.
<h3>Timing</h3>
The timing of your webinar is very important to the audience members because a time that can create a conflict with other activities creates a higher barrier of entry for your target audience to join. Most people join webinars between 11 am to 2 pm during the middle of the work-week.

This may be the best time to host your webinar. However, ensure that your target audience is in the right time zone when you set your webinar timing. If a large portion of your target audience would not be joining the webinar from your time zone, cater to their time zone to ensure a larger audience to your webinar.
<h3>Punctuality</h3>
Punctuality is important because people joining your webinar would not appreciate it if they feel as if they are having their time wasted. Always join the platform earlier than the advertised start time on your webinar.

This gives you time to set up and ensure that the tech is working before your audience members join. In addition, this practice allows you to begin your webinar on time without you rushing to get onto the platform and seeming unprepared.
<h3>Stay on Schedule</h3>
Ensure that your webinar starts and ends on the allotted time that was advertised. Your audience members have their personal lives and have other commitments that they may need to attend.

They have allocated the time that you have advertised to join your webinar and starting late could make them feel like you do not value their time and ending late could also generate the same feelings.

Do not make your audience need to leave your webinar before it ends. This sets a bad precedent that can produce a feeling that you may not value their time. Starting and ending on the advertised time can create a positive experience for your audience members.
<h2 id="Practice">8. Practice Makes Perfect</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16142" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/value-copy-62@2x-1.png" alt="" width="1920" height="1030" />

Practicing before you present ensures not only that you are smooth while you present, but can also direct you towards some potential mistakes you have made when preparing your slides or script.
<h3>Smooth Out Issues</h3>
Smoothing out all your issues, tech, or presentation related before your webinar. Any mistake, even one that can be out of your control can convey a perception of unprofessionalism. What you can do is practice and smooth out all the issues that you can find before your webinar date.

Eliminating most of your potential issues is the best way to ensure that your webinar goes smoothly when the day comes.
<h2 id="present">9. Present Your Webinar</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17365" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sem-webinars@2x-1.png" alt="webinar speaker" width="1920" height="1030" />

It is now time to present your webinar. With your practice and all your technology set up, your webinar should run smoothly. If there are any technological hiccups or any other kind of issues, acknowledge them and try to get them fixed right away.

Not acknowledging potential issues create a feeling of being nonchalant about your audience member’s experience and can deter them from being repeat customers to your webinars.
<h3>Present FAQ’s</h3>
Presenting frequently asked questions before your Q&amp;A session at the end of your webinar can help answer many of the potential questions your audience members may have before they ask them. This acknowledges that your audience members’ questions are valid and corroborate that they are asking an intelligent question.
<h2 id="follow">10. Follow Up with Your Audience Members</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17934" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/survey-webinar@2x.png" alt="webinar survey questions" width="1920" height="1030" />

Following up with your audience members after the webinar creates a connection with them and can convince them to come back for another webinar. Not only can following up create repeat customers but can also help you gain insights on your webinars and how to improve them.
<h3>Send Surveys</h3>
Send surveys to your audience members to fill out. These do not need to be solely after your webinar, you can also do send them out before, during, or after. Our guide <a href="https://blog.eventbank.com/webinar-survey-questions/">here</a> can help you figure out what questions to ask on which particular survey.

These surveys can help you gain valuable insight into how your webinars are performing and how you can improve them for your audience members, rather than relying on that gut feeling. These surveys can improve your overall webinar as well as showing that you value your audience member’s feedback.
<h3>Webinar Recording</h3>
Sending out the webinar recording can help audience members who had to miss your webinar but already paid for it still be able to gain value for the information presented in your webinar.

These recordings create more value for your audience members because they will be able to go back to the recording and refresh their memory on the topics presented.
<h2 id="consistent">11. Be Consistent</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16810" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-phone@2x.png" alt="mobile notifications" width="2400" height="1288" />

Consistency is key in today's day and age. People crave consistency because it develops into a feeling of trust. Consistency can come in two forms, hosting webinars on a consistent plan and keeping your formats consistent.
<h3>Consistent Schedule</h3>
Ensure that you schedule your webinars consistently. Doing that can ensure that your repeat audience members will have the time free during the time you present your webinar. This increases the possibility that they will rejoin your webinars and ensure you have a larger audience.
<h3>Consistent Format</h3>
A consistent format can be in the way that your webinar is presented or the slides that you create for your webinars. Ensure that a level of consistency is achieved for audience members to develop trust in your webinar. As your audience members begin to trust your webinars, they will start attending more of them.
<h2>Additional Resources</h2>
We hope that all these tips can help you start your own webinar and if you want more tips visit <a href="https://blog.eventbank.com/successful-webinar-strategies/">our guide on how to create a successful webinar.</a> Remember that all these steps are a guideline but do not have to be followed 100% for you to create a successful webinar of your own.

If you’re looking to enhance your webinars and create a unique webinar experience for your audience members, <a href="https://get.eventbank.com/webinar-solution/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=webinarnewbies">Book a Demo</a> with EventBank. We'll show you how our platform can make your webinars one-of-a-kind with our platform to increase your audience members' experiences.
<p style="text-align: center;">Or submit the form below.</p>
[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="#top">Back to Top.</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18493</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-07-03 08:31:28]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-07-03 08:31:28]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[simple-webinar-tutorial]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="event-management"><![CDATA[Event Management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="webinar"><![CDATA[webinar]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11 Simple Steps to Start Your Own Webinar for Newbies]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Here's 11 simple steps to start your own webinar that make it easy, fun, and engaging for both you and your audience.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18525]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>EventBank Expands to Latin American Markets</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/eventbank-latin-america-expansion/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jeremy]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18536</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="#espanol"><strong>Leer la versión en Español</strong></a>

<strong>EventBank, a SaaS company specializing in events, associations, and chamber management software, has expanded to the Latin American market as their software continues to transform professional communities across the globe.</strong>

Tysons, Virginia- Today, <a href="http://www.eventbank.com/?utm_source=pressrelease&amp;utm_medium=latam">EventBank</a>, a cloud-based membership and event management SaaS company expanded to Latin America in order to better serve organizations in those markets. EventBank is excited to announce they have deployed a team in Mexico City dedicated to serve its LATAM customers. EventBank’s all-in-one software is already helping organizations in Mexico, Colombia, and many more countries.

EventBank’s all-in-one software includes a CRM &amp; contact database, event management tools, email marketing features, ticketing, finance management, and more. EventBank has already begun assisting organizations in the LATAM markets with their events and membership strategies and they hope to continue serving more organizations in Latin American markets with this expansion. Regarding the expansion, CEO of EventBank, Eric Schmidt, says “we look forward to helping organizations in the LATAM market grow with the help of our software. The EventBank platform is uniquely positioned to help organizations overcome their challenges regardless of where they are located across the globe.”
<b> </b>
This expansion comes just a few weeks after some other big news from EventBank, as they recently introduced their community and webinar engagement solutions which allow clients to build their professional communities in a digital environment as well as launch Webinars directly from the platform. With the COVID-19 forcing organizations to transition to a digital environment, EventBank has adapted to help clients not only survive but thrive in an increasingly online setting. EventBank looks forward to continuing their 2020 success in these LATAM markets as they look to continue their mission to transform the way professional communities enable and enrich relationships.

<hr />

<b>About EventBank </b>EventBank is a leading provider of the cloud solutions that provide associations, event organizers, Chambers of Commerce, agencies, marketers, businesses, and NGOs with a full suite of tools designed to streamline operations, modernize processes, and eliminate engagement challenges. EventBank’s innovative all-in-one solutions combine the best event management, membership management, email marketing, CRM, Finance, Project Management, and mobile apps. EventBank is currently present in 50+ countries around the world.

<b>Media Contact:</b>
Jeremy Smith
<a href="mailto:jeremy.smith@eventbank.com">jeremy.smith@eventbank.com
</a><a href="tel:+15713582822">+1 571-358-2822</a>

<b>Contacto de Media de Espanol </b>
Pamela Garcia Gonzalez
<a href="mailto:pamela.gonzalez@eventbank.com">pamela.gonzalez@eventbank.com</a>
<a href="tel:+5215539750191">+52 155-3975-0191</a>
<h1 id="espanol">EventBank se expande a los mercados Latinoamericanos</h1>
<strong>EventBank, es una compañía SaaS especializada en sistemas de administración de Eventos, para Asociaciones y Cámaras que se ha expandido al mercado de Latinoamérica a medida que su software continúa transformando comunidades profesionales en todo el mundo.</strong>

Tysons, Virginia- Hoy, <a href="http://www.eventbank.com/?utm_source=pressrelease&amp;utm_medium=latames">EventBank</a>, una empresa SaaS basada en la nube especializada en gestión de eventos y membresías se expandió a América Latina para servir mejor a las organizaciones en esos mercados. EventBank se complace al anunciar que han desplegado un equipo en la Ciudad de México dedicado a servir a sus clientes de LATAM. La solución todo-en-uno de EventBank ya se encuentra ayudando a organizaciones en México, Colombia y otros países.

El software todo-en-uno de EventBank incluye CRM y base de contactos, herramientas de administración de eventos, funciones de e-mail marketing, boletos, administración de finanzas, y mucho más. EventBank ya ha comenzado a ayudar a organizaciones en los mercados de LATAM con sus eventos y estrategias de membresía y espera continuar sirviendo a más organizaciones en los mercados latinoamericanos con esta expansión. Sobre la expansión, el CEO de EventBank, Eric Schmidt, dice “esperamos ayudar a las organizaciones en el mercado de LATAM a crecer con la ayuda de nuestro software. La plataforma de EventBank está en una posición única para ayudar a las organizaciones a superar sus desafíos independientemente de dónde se encuentren en todo el mundo".
<b> </b>
Esta expansión viene sólo después de unas semanas de otras grandes noticias de EventBank, recientemente presentaron sus soluciones de fidelización de la comunidad y seminarios web que permiten a los clientes construir comunidades profesionales en un entorno digital, así como lanzar seminarios web directamente desde la plataforma. Con el coronavirus forzando a las organizaciones a emigrar a un ambiente digital, EventBank se ha adaptado para ayudar a los clientes no solo a sobrevivir, sino a prosperar en un entorno cada vez más digital. EventBank espera continuar con su éxito durante este 2020 en estos mercados de LATAM mientras busca continuar con su misión de transformar la forma en que las comunidades profesionales establecen y enriquecen sus relaciones.

<b>Sobre EventBank: </b>EventBank es un proveedor líder de soluciones en la nube que proporciona a las asociaciones, organizadores de eventos, Cámaras de Comercio, agencias, mercadólogos, empresas, y ONGs un conjunto completo de herramientas diseñadas para agilizar las operaciones, modernizar procesos, y eliminar los desafíos de la fidelización. La innovadora solución todo-en-uno de EventBank combina la mejor administración de eventos y membresías, campañas de e-mail marketing, CRM, Finanzas, gestión de proyectos y aplicaciones móviles. EventBank actualmente está presente en más de 50 países de todo el mundo.

<hr />

<b>Contacto de Media:</b>
Jeremy Smith
<a href="mailto:jeremy.smith@eventbank.com">jeremy.smith@eventbank.com
</a><a href="tel:+15713582822">+1 571-358-2822</a>

<b>Contacto de Media de Espanol </b>
Pamela Garcia Gonzalez
<a href="mailto:pamela.gonzalez@eventbank.com">pamela.gonzalez@eventbank.com</a>
<a href="tel:+5215539750191">+52 155-3975-0191</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18536</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-07-07 10:45:49]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-07-07 10:45:49]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[eventbank-latin-america-expansion]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="eventbank"><![CDATA[EventBank]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="expansion"><![CDATA[expansion]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="news"><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news-press-releases"><![CDATA[News &amp; Press Releases]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="office"><![CDATA[office]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[48]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[%%title%% %%page%%]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tysons, Virginia- Today, EventBank, a cloud-based membership and event management SaaS company expanded to Latin America.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18556]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>How the National Rural Education Association Increased their Memberships During a Global Pandemic</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/success-story-nrea/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jeremy]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18572</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, Allen Pratt, Executive Director of the <a href="https://www.nrea.net/">National Rural Education Association</a> was looking to find new software to better serve his organization. His software at the time, Netforum Pro, was one that he inherited when he came to the organization and it wasn’t exactly easy to use. Allen Pratt explained he “didn’t like the user-friendliness of it, updating of information and adding things to the newsletter. It just didn’t flow right for me and I didn’t like how it was very difficult for people to log in and renew their membership. We needed to fix that immediately.” Some of the main challenges NREA was facing were engaging with their members, easily updating their weekly newsletter, and updating member information and invoicing.

As they searched for a new solution to help manage their association, they came across EventBank. They joined in on a demo and were impressed with what they saw, but more importantly, Allen explained “being able to practice on the EventBank system before we committed was awesome” as new clients are able to use a demo account before committing to any contract. After considering the ease of use and how it could help fix the challenges NREA was facing, Allen determined that “EventBank was the best choice for us.”

In February of 2020, the National Rural Education Association (NREA) signed on with EventBank. Allen said that “if you can export your data on a drive, you can match it up to Eventbank and its very simple” to migrate data to the EventBank system. Regarding the onboarding process as a whole, Allen mentioned that “it’s nice to work with someone who cares about what we’re doing, and the onboarding procedure was really good. Brian helped us with onboarding, and he was great and easy to work with. He worked with us and got us onboarded in about 2 weeks.”

Just a few weeks later, the coronavirus began shutting down most of the United States. The coronavirus has had a lasting impact on the association industry since, so how did the NREA manage to survive? They were able to do so because they had a powerful association management platform to help them along the way. Allen Pratt mentioned that “we're probably one of the few membership organizations that have actually grown this year.” You heard that right. The National Rural Education Association was not only able to survive but GROW during the global pandemic.

The following are some of the ways that EventBank has been able to help the National Rural Education Association grow throughout this year:
<h2>The Weekly Newsletter</h2>
The NREA sends out a weekly newsletter to all of its contacts that are tracked in EventBank’s CRM. Allen mentioned that “the newsletter has been well received and has been really great for us” and “it helps us to get our information to our members quickly, it also helps us to communicate and people can easily sign up when they find out were a useful source of information.” As we’ve seen throughout the coronavirus pandemic, staying in constant communication with members is essential to associations and the NREA has been able to do that effectively with EventBank.

Allen also mentioned that its simple to communicate with different contacts in different ways saying that “if anyone has an email address in our system, we can send them the newsletter but if we just want to send things to members, it’s easy to do that too. EventBank helps to reach different people at different touchpoints in the organization.” Allen also mentioned that “right now we only send out our newsletter every Friday, but as school comes back in the fall we’ll start sending more emails through EventBank’s system.” Since signing with EventBank in February 2020, the NREA has sent over 43 thousand emails through the EventBank platform.
<h2>Boosting Memberships</h2>
As mentioned earlier, the NREA has actually increased their memberships since signing on with EventBank. Allen mentions that “it’s already increased our membership based on renewals based on how we use the platform” because “anyone that’s had a contact point with our organization since 2008, we have now rolled them into EventBank and we’re now picking up members that fell off the chart in our old system.” Because of EventBank’s high-level data analytics, the NREA can find contacts who previously may have slipped through the cracks and target them more effectively.

From seeing who is opening their newsletters to who hasn’t yet renewed their memberships for the year, they can track all of this on EventBank and have used this info to boost their membership. Currently, the NREA is tracking over 5000 contacts through EventBank’s powerful CRM.
<div class="quote">
<div class="person"><img class="wp-image-3600 alignleft" style="border-radius: 50%;" src="https://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/allan-pratt@2x-204x204.png" alt="Allen Pratt" width="173" height="173" /></div>
<blockquote><em>“we’ve increased tremendously to the point where we’ve already surpassed our goal in membership for the year, which is partly because we’re able to gain memberships from ones we used to miss out on in our old system” </em>
<h6><strong>Allen Pratt,</strong> Executive Director of the <a href="https://www.nrea.net/">National Rural Education Association</a></h6>
</blockquote>
</div>
<h2>Automation and an All-in-One Solution</h2>
EventBank has made many processes easier for the NREA such as sending out invoices. Allen said that “the automation part of sending out invoices saves me time. I don’t have to mail out invoices anymore.” Automated invoices through EventBank are certainly a benefit that helps the NREA turn a tedious process into an automated one. The NREA is also happy with the all-in-one aspect of EventBank. Because of the coronavirus, Allen mentioned that “we lost our event for the fall, so we're switching to online in November” but “down the road, we're looking at event management, and we already have that built-in so we can handle it in our one-stop-shop.”

EventBank empowers the NREA to not only handle their email marketing, CRM, and invoices but also their event management, all in one place. The NREA is even considering upgrading their contract to include the new community engagement solution that can help the membership-based organization connect and engage their communities in a digital setting. The best part is the EventBank platform communicates amongst its different modules so the data can help reach people more effectively.

Signing on with EventBank has empowered the NREA to boost their membership even during the global pandemic. Allen has a message for other association leaders: “if you’re looking for a platform that you can actually talk to people and know the people you’re working with and it’s a phone call away, EventBank is the way to go. The interface is easy for us and easy for our members but the fact that if I have an issue, I can email someone and get an email back from people higher up in the company is great. I emailed someone recently about the community feature and the CEO responded right away.”

Not only can EventBank’s platform empower organizations to grow, but it also does so while providing excellent customer service.

To see how EventBank can help you boost your memberships, book a demo today!

[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18572</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-07-15 15:15:10]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-07-15 15:15:10]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[success-story-nrea]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="associations-chambers"><![CDATA[Associations &amp; Chambers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="chambers"><![CDATA[chambers]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="memberships"><![CDATA[memberships]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="success-stories"><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="success-story"><![CDATA[Success Story]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[245]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The National Rural Education Association signed on with EventBank in February 2020 and has increased their membership since despite the global pandemic.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18573]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[How the NREA Increased their Memberships During a Global Pandemic]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020-07-14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>14 Donation Software that Get Causes Off the Ground</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/donation-software/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 07:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carl]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18607</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Fundraising efforts can be stressful especially if your company has limited resources because it is often a highly time-consuming task. However, there are many donation software choices out there that not only help you accept donations from a wider range of sources, but can also help you manage your donors and your fundraising campaigns.

Looking for more of an <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/best-event-management-software/">event management software</a>? Or a <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/best-membership-management-software/">membership management software</a> selection?
<h3 id="top">Quick Reads</h3>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; vertical-align: top;"><a href="#donorbox">Donor Box</a>
<a href="#qgiv">Qgiv</a>
<a href="#neoncrm">NeonCrm</a>
<a href="#fundly">Fundly</a>
<a href="#funraise">Funraise</a></td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; vertical-align: top;"><a href="#onecause">One Cause</a>
<a href="#causevox">CauseVox</a>
<a href="#doubledonation">Double the Donation</a>
<a href="#snowball">Snowball Fundraising</a>
<a href="#soapbox">Soapbox Engagement</a></td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; vertical-align: top;"><a href="#donorsearch">Donor Search</a>
<a href="#mogli">Mogli SMS</a>
<a href="#facebook">Facebook Fundraisers</a>
<a href="#paypal">Paypal</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>What is Donation Software?</h2>
Donation software often comes with CRM management systems that help you manage and track all your donors for your fundraising campaigns. Not only does it track your current donors, but it will also source potential donors for you to expand your donor list.
<h2>How can it help you?</h2>
<h3>Efficiency</h3>
Donation Software can help you reduce employees’ time by automatically inputting data as well as automatically searching for potential donors for you. In addition, the software can help you lower your fundraising costs. This means your employees will be able to use this new time to create better relationships with your donors as well as lowering your costs.
<h3>Accuracy</h3>
With software inputting your data instead of an employee, there will be a reduction of errors such as duplicate entries or data entry errors. It will also more accurately track the interaction your employees have with your donors to track the pattern and trends.
<h3>Higher donor responses</h3>
As the software tracks the patterns and trends of donors, staff interactions with donors, and donor demographics, it can source potential donors for your company that will have a higher possibility of contributing a donation. The software can also analyze trends and for specific campaigns, it can target the donors who would be more likely to donate to those campaigns.
<h2 id="donorbox">1. <a href="https://donorbox.org/">Donorbox</a></h2>
<img class="notfull aligncenter" src="https://d1sssn74k2rfxk.cloudfront.net/assets/landing-pages/hero-image-1x-01788391cd37943187f5d140fe871f2c8d1856c49a6eec025bcb1ad84fb564ec.webp" alt="Nonprofit fundraising - donations forms for nonprofits" width="495" height="414" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Accepts different types of payments
</b>Donorbox allows donors to pay in a variety of ways including Apple Pay, Google Pay, Paypal, and Bank Payments</li>
 	<li><b>Subscription Donations
</b>This makes it both easy for your company to receive donations on a recurring basis and makes it easier for your donors to make recurring payments without needing to re-input her or his information every month.</li>
 	<li><b>Company Gift Matching
</b>This feature allows companies to match donations given by other donors without manually needing to go through the process of making the donation. Donors themselves can encourage their companies to match the donations they make.</li>
 	<li><b>Multi-Currency Support
</b>Donorbox accepts over 20 currencies from around the world and allows you to accept donations from all over the world, making it easier for you international donors to support your cause.</li>
 	<li><b>Multi-Language Integration
</b>Donorbox supports 11 different languages, making it easier for you and your donors to navigate the platform.</li>
 	<li><b>Secure Payments
</b>All payments on Donorbox are protected by encryption technology and there is also an anti-fraud system in place.</li>
 	<li><b>Donor Profiles
</b>Individual Profiles are made for every donor where they can edit their recurring donations are making new recurring donations.</li>
 	<li><b>Analytics
</b>Analytics are important in donation software because it can help with predicting trends and sourcing new donors and Donorbox offers these features to help you streamline in the process of accepting donations.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
Donorbox has no upfront costs on its platform, <strong>it charges 1.5% of the monthly donations made</strong> as well as different processing fees for the different payment types.

ACH bank payments are capped at $5 with the processing fee being 0.8% + $0.3 per transaction

Paypal and Stripe Payments have a processing fee of 2.9% + $0.3 per transaction

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="qgiv">2. <a href="https://www.qgiv.com/">Qgiv</a></h2>
<img class="notfull aligncenter" src="https://www.qgiv.com/_resources/images/feature-fundraising-thermometer.png" alt="qgiv non profit screenshot" width="555" height="541" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Text Fundraising
</b>Text fundraising is a Qgiv feature that has two different features to support easy donations for donors. They can either donate a certain amount that then will be reflected upon their next phone bill or they can initiate a gift via text and visit a mobile form to complete the donation.</li>
 	<li><b>Facebook Donation Forms
</b>This feature allows donors to enter a form on your Facebook page to make a donation without leaving your page. This allows for a lower barrier for the donors to leap over to give the donations they want.</li>
 	<li><b>Peer to Peer
</b>This allows your donors to help you raise funds on your behalf. There are ways for your donors to gamify your event that can help them raise more funds on your behalf.</li>
 	<li><b>Content Management System
</b>A content management system can help you design your custom forms with ease without needing previous experience. This makes it easier for you to design the perfect form for your company without hiring a professional.</li>
 	<li><b>Gift Assist
</b>This feature allows your donors to, if they are willing, to pay for the processing costs so it does not hinder your company when these costs cut into your donations.</li>
 	<li><b>Kiosks
</b>Mobile Kiosks on your phone can be used to take donations in person straight on your iPhone through Qgiv’s mobile app.</li>
 	<li><b>Donor Accounts
</b>Each donor will be given an account that can help them make donations more easily to you. It includes a payment methods management system as well as the ability for them to manage their donations.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
Qgiv’s pricing starts with no upfront fees but with <strong>a transaction fee of 3.95% and $0.30 on every donation received on the platform</strong>.

However, if your company wants to choose a package option with different sets of features, the prices range from $10/month to $399/month.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="neoncrm">3. <a href="https://www.neoncrm.com/">NeonCRM</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://www.neoncrm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/neoncrm-device-screenshots-updated.png" alt="neoncrm-device-screenshots-updated" width="960" height="529" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Relationship Tracking
</b>The NeonCRM Relationship Tracking feature can help you manage your donors and engage them when planning your events.</li>
 	<li><b>Volunteer Management
</b>This allows you to track your volunteer hours as well and manage them by assigning them different tasks all on the platform. Volunteer sign up forms can also be found here where you can create custom forms for volunteers to sign up.</li>
 	<li><b>Email Marketing
</b>The NeonCRM email marketing tool allows you to build and send you campaign emails as well as automatic emails to be sent when specific actions are made by your donors to create conditional emails. Here you can also manage your email audiences to ensure that the right donors are receiving your emails.</li>
 	<li><b>Survey Builder
</b>The Survey Builder allows the user to create custom surveys that can be adjusted with various types of fields. You can include standard fields that show up on every survey as well as custom fields that can be sent to specific accounts on the system.</li>
 	<li><b>Analytics
</b>The analytics on NeonCRM can be customized to the user’s needs. This allows you to see only the things you need to see in easily understandable graphics.</li>
 	<li><b>Payment Types
</b>NeonCRM takes different payment types such as Debit Cards, Credit Cards, and Checks which allow your vast donor base to donate money in the best way that works for them. All the payments are encrypted and have automatic fraud detection</li>
 	<li><b>Materials Tracking
</b>NeonCRM also allows you to track your promotional materials so you can keep inventory any time and order materials that may be lacking.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
NeonCRM starts its pricing at $50/month with basic features but prices can increase to $200/months for more advanced features for larger firms.

They also have a standard processing fee of 2.9% + $0.30 per transaction.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="fundly">4. <a href="http://fundly.com/">Fundly</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://cdn0.capterra-static.com/screenshots/2084685/64991.png" alt="fundly crm" width="960" height="478" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Customizable Donation Pages
</b>Funding allows you to customize all your donation pages to your liking. These pages will be listed on Fundly for potential donors to view and donate to a cause they support.</li>
 	<li><b>Integrated Social Media
</b>The integrated social media function on Fundly allows you to promote your fundraisers more easily straight to your different social media accounts. This allows your friends and followers to become donors as well as attract new potential donors.</li>
 	<li><b>Integrated Blog
</b>The integrated blog on Fundly allows nonprofits to have a blog that can update donors on the fundraising process as well as source new potential donors.</li>
 	<li><b>Mobile Friendly
</b>With a mobile-friendly platform, all donors can donate on the go which lowers the barrier of entry for donors to make donations. This creates a higher likelihood for more donations</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
There is no upfront fee required for funding but there is <strong>a 4.9% deducted for Fundly on all donations made in the platform as well as a credit card processing fee of 2.9% +$0.30 per transaction</strong>.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="funraise">5. <a href="https://www.funraise.org/">Funraise</a></h2>
<img class="alignleft" src="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5d6eb414117b673d211598f2/5da779f3b66ccc53238d60c6_home-feature-slider-donation-forms.jpg" alt="funraise" width="1400" height="1202" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Social Fundraising
</b>Funraise’s social fundraising allows you to fundraise on your favorite social media platforms. This allows a secure way to raise money on social media platforms where all your followers can see and spread the word about your fundraiser.</li>
 	<li><b>Fundraising Websites
</b>Funraise helps you create custom websites with an easy to use website maker. This allows you to create the website you want for your fundraisers.</li>
 	<li><b>Automated Emails
</b>The automated email function allows you to create different custom emails without needing the knowledge of HTML. It allows you to create your emails easily with pre-made templates to impress your donors.</li>
 	<li><b>Funraise App
</b>Allows you to accept donations on the go. It does not require you to implement donor data entry because all donations sync with your Funraise account.</li>
 	<li><b>Peer-to-Peer Fundraising
</b>Funraise also supports peer-to-peer fundraising. This allows your most dedicated donors to spread the word about your fundraiser and accept more donations and expand your donor base.</li>
 	<li><b>Donation Forms
</b>Funraise offers donation forms that are customizable. This allows you to collect donations straight from your website while incorporating your company's branding on the form.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
Funraise does not offer packages but<strong> they create custom quotes based on what you need</strong> from your donor software.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="onecause">6. <a href="https://www.onecause.com/">OneCause</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://a.fsdn.com/con/app/proj/onecause.s/screenshots/OneCause-AuctionsPanel.png/1000/auto/1" alt="onecause" width="1000" height="483" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Peer to Peer
</b>OneCause supports peer to peer fundraising which can help you expand your donor base and spread the word about our fundraiser.</li>
 	<li><b>Events
</b>Allows nonprofits to sell tickets and collect donations for events without needing to download a new piece of software.</li>
 	<li><b>Text2Give
</b>Allows mobile donations which create a larger donor base through a lower barrier of entry.</li>
 	<li><b>SmartPay
</b>Allows secure payments and payment management at events or for donations.</li>
 	<li><b>Peer to Peer
</b>OneCause also supports peer to peer fundraising which can increase your donations and your donor base.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
OneCause does not offer set packages but it offers many tiers for companies to choose from and <strong>pricing will vary.</strong>

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="causevox">7. <a href="https://www.causevox.com/">CauseVox</a></h2>
<img class="notfull aligncenter" src="https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_lossy,ret_img/https://www.causevox.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/purposely-simple.png" alt="cause vox" width="596" height="739" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Peer to Peer
</b>CauseVox has integrated peer to peer fundraising to have your most dedicated donors to find other donors and direct them to your fundraisers.</li>
 	<li><b>CRM
</b>CauseVox’s integrated CRM will automatically update contact profiles as well as segment contacts into different groups. It also helps you keep track of donation progress and trends.</li>
 	<li><b>Donation Form
</b>An easy to use donation form makes it easier for your donors to donate. It allows monthly recurring donations, as well as one time donations with smart, save information. The form will remember donor information and pre-fill the donor details. It doesn’t hurt that the donation forms are also mobile-friendly.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
<strong>There are three tiers to CauseVox’s pricing.</strong>

The first tier costs $0/month but includes a processing fee of 2.2% + $0.30 per donation.

The second tier costs $139/month when billed annually but $185/month when billed monthly without commitments. This tier comes with more features but still has a processing fee of 4.25% on the platform along with a processing fee of 2.2% + $0.30 per donation via Stripe and Paypal.

The top tier includes many more features and it costs $245/month when billed annually and $285/month when billed monthly. It also includes a platform fee of 3% along with a processing fee of 2.2% + $0.30 per donation via Stripe and Paypal.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="doubledonation">8. <a href="https://doublethedonation.com/">Double the Donation</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://doublethedonation.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Double_the_Donation_Matching_Gift_Tools_Overview-1.png" alt="Double the Donation Matching Gift Tools Overview" width="1000" height="734" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Desktop and Mobile Friendly
</b>This creates a larger donor base who can search and identify their match requests from any device, whether it be a mobile, tablet, or desktop device. The ease of access lowers the barrier of entry to the platform.</li>
 	<li><b>360Match
</b>This feature allows Double the Donation users to track the status of their matching gifts as well as identify gift eligibility and send custom automated emails to drive higher matched donations.</li>
 	<li><b>Matching Donations
</b>The platform is highly based on the idea that people can donate for large organizations to match their donations as well.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
Double the Donation comes with 2 packages, a premium package, and the 360MatchPro package.

<strong>The Premium package costs $499/year</strong> and the 360MatchPro, aimed at institutions with more than $25000 annual matching gift revenues costs at $3000/year.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="snowball">9. <a href="https://snowballfundraising.com/">Snowball Fundraising</a></h2>
<img class="notfull aligncenter" src="https://softwareconnect.com/images/screenshots/screenshot-snowball-custom-donation-page-348127" alt="snowball fundraising" width="800" height="500" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Text-to-Give
</b>This feature allows you to accept and ask for donations through text with custom messages. It also allows you to sell event tickets through these features.</li>
 	<li><b>Live Event Thermometers
</b>This gamifies the event to create more excitement for your donors to track your success.</li>
 	<li><b>Ticketing
</b>Sell event tickets for your fundraisers and share the receipts with the buyers. You can also get a headcount while registering attendees for your event.</li>
 	<li><b>Customizable Forms
</b>Customizable forms allow you to design the perfect form that you would like to send out for specific fundraisers.</li>
 	<li><b>Digital Megaphone
</b>This feature lets you broadcast on all your social media accounts about your fundraiser to increase donor pools and increase your donations.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
There are three pricing plans for Snowball Fundraising.

<strong>The Essential plan is the cheapest and has no upfront costs</strong> but includes a processing fee of 2.9% + $0.30 per transaction.

<strong>The Premium plans cost at $549/year</strong> with a lower processing fee of 2.2% + $0.30 per transaction.

<strong>The highest tier is the Enterprise which starts at $999/year</strong> and is for organizations that process large amounts of donations.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="soapbox">10. <a href="https://www.soapboxengage.com/">Soapbox Engagement</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://www.soapboxengage.com/templates/sbxengage/images/device-app-landingvideo.png" alt="Soapbox Engage apps" width="939" height="547" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Donation Forms
</b>This feature allows for integrated Salesforce donations. It allows visitors to customize their own gift amount. This also includes a customizable confirmation letter than can be integrated with videos and images.</li>
 	<li><b>Add-ons
</b>Add on features for Soapbox Engagement include Peer to Peer fundraising and custom designs for users.</li>
 	<li><b>Salesforce
</b>Salesforce integration allows you to manage all aspects of your fundraiser. All forms, donations emails, and donors are saved to salesforce to allow you an easy way to track the progress of your fundraisers.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
The pricing structure on Soapbox Engage is dependent on the number of apps that are being used.

<strong>Soapbox Engage starts at $49/month per app for non-profits</strong>.

<strong>The standard plan starts at $99/month per app.</strong>

<strong>The unlimited standard plan is $349/month.</strong>

<strong>The unlimited plan for non-profit organizations is $199/month.</strong>

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="donorsearch">11. <a href="https://www.donorsearch.net/">Donor Search</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://neonone.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/DonorSearchwebsite.png" alt="DonorSearch - Neon One" width="900" height="900" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Comprehensive Database
</b>The comprehensive database of Donor Search can help you search for potential donors for your fundraisers. It helps you screen for prospective donors in a more effective manner.</li>
 	<li><b>CRM Platform Integration
</b>The CRM platform integration allows you to manage potential donors more easily. You can integrate with many CRM platforms including Salesforce.</li>
 	<li><b>Wealth Screening Service
</b>This service screens for prospective donors using wealth data and previous involvement with non-profits. This can help your organization find donors more effectively because it can find donors with a history of philanthropic activities.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
<strong>Pricing on Donor Search is largely quote-based</strong>, established on what features are needed for your organization.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="mogli">12. <a href="https://www.mogli.com/">Mogli SMS</a></h2>
<img class="notfull aligncenter" src="https://omaticsoftware.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/top-salesforce-apps-for-nonprofits-moglisms.jpg" alt="mogli sms" width="570" height="345" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Mobile Engagement
</b>This software company prides itself on mobile engagement. Many of its features are available through texts such as one-on-one chats, bulk messaging, and chatbot. For international consumers, it also has the ability to use Whatsapp for unlimited service internationally.</li>
 	<li><b>Text-to-Vote
</b>Using the text-to-vote function you can see real-time voting on your integrated Salesforce dashboard.</li>
 	<li><b>Chatbot
</b>Automated conversations can help you answer conversations when you are not readily available. This creates an amazing service for customers even when you are away.</li>
 	<li><b>Bulk Messaging
</b>Send messages to specific groups which can help increase efficiency in keeping in contact with clients as well as maintaining a good relationship.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
The pricing structure for Mogli SMS is based on a 4 tier system: Starter, Standard, Elite, and Enterprise.

<strong>Starter tier costs at 250/month </strong>and billed annually at $3000/year.

<strong>Standard tier costs $460/month </strong>and billed annually at $5500.

<strong>Elite tier comes in at $670/month </strong>and billed annually at $8000.

<strong> Enterprise tier is $1090/month </strong>and billed annually at $13000.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="facebook">13. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/fundraisers/">Facebook Fundraisers</a></h2>
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://assets.entrepreneur.com/content/3x2/2000/20170403151814-facebook-fundraising.jpeg" alt="facebook fundraisers" width="2000" height="1334" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>Social Media Fundraising
</b>Facebook integrated fundraising is integrated straight on the social media platform to raise awareness more easily. They also allow you to fundraise on their other platform, Instagram.</li>
 	<li><b>Recurring Donations
</b>This feature allows for recurring monthly gifts for donors to easily give every month without needing to go through the donation process again.</li>
 	<li><b>Fundraising Stickers
</b>Fundraising Stickers allow organizations to fundraise on their Facebook stories not solely on their pages. This adds a layer of promotion to the fundraiser.</li>
 	<li><b>Live Video Donation
</b>Live video donations allow you to give people an inside look at your organization or answer questions about the fundraiser while people are donating without needing to rent out a physical space.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
Non-profits on the Facebook platform to process their donations pay no fees.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2 id="paypal">14. <a href="https://www.paypal.com/">Paypal</a></h2>
<img class="notfull aligncenter" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/55f62c4ce4b02545cc6ee94f/1591282936038-8LUMSH348ETW41B7H91J/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAOnxrLUr4TxkX1VphGXtWJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIMjdt9L3l8uzvkvzr5oTTs61KLyFUDrxKJTPe1qObU_8KMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/screenshot-Milford-Miami-Chamber-Commerge.JPG?format=500w" alt="chamber of commerce donation via paypal" width="500" height="414" />
<h3>Top Features</h3>
<ul>
 	<li><b>In-Person Fundraising
</b>Using Paypal Here you can accept donations using donors’ preferred paying method. This makes it easier for donations at in-person fundraisers.</li>
 	<li><b>Embedded Donate Button
</b>The Paypal Embedded donate button can be integrated on non-profit’s websites. This allows for an easy method for donors to contribute a gift.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pricing</h3>
<strong>Paypal Here charges a processing fee of 2.7% per transaction</strong>. And for the Donation button embedded in your website, they charge a processing fee of <strong>2.9% + $0.30 per transaction</strong>.

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>
<h2>Wrapping it Up</h2>
Each donation software has its benefits and features that work better than others and some hit just a niche market. Ensure you pick the one that integrates with your organization smoothly. This is just a preliminary list for you to understand to basic features of each software.

Do your own research on the one you think is right for you before you pick it. We hope our list is comprehensive and helps you have a good idea of which software your organization wants. We hope that your process for picking the right Donation software for you goes smoothly and the one you pick is the right one for your organization.

EventBank is about to have its own news concerning donations, so stay tuned. In the meanwhile, consider <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=donationsoftware"><strong>booking a demo</strong></a> to get yourself up to speed on our other great features like CRM, Email Marketing, Event Management, Ticketing, and more before we start rolling out the big guns.
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Or fill out the form below</strong></p>
[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Top</strong></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18607</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-07-13 07:57:10]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-07-13 07:57:10]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[donation-software]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="associations-chambers"><![CDATA[Associations &amp; Chambers]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="donation-software"><![CDATA[donation software]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="donations"><![CDATA[donations]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="funding"><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="organizations"><![CDATA[organizations]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[14 Donation Software that Get Causes Off the Ground]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[14 Donation Software that helps your organization collect, manage, distribute, and account for all your fundraising needs and get your cause off the ground.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[90]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[donation software]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18634]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Ultimate Guide to Membership Marketing</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/membership-marketing-guide/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 07:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[robert]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18678</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Membership marketing is the main activity your organization should be implementing to <b><span style="color: #00b832;">drive new members</span>, <span style="color: #00b832;">renew current members</span>, </b>and <span style="color: #00b832;"><b>bring back past members</b></span>.

Let's dig in.
<h3 id="top">Table of Contents</h3>
<ol>
 	<li><a href="#journey">Outline the Member-Journey</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#software">Using the Right Software</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#outbound">Outbound Member Campaigns</a>
<ol>
 	<li><a href="#email">Email Marketing</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#socialnetworking">Social Media Networking</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#events">Events &amp; Conference Networking</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
 	<li><a href="#inbound">Inbound Member Campaigns</a>
<ol>
 	<li><a href="#socialpresence">Social Media Presence</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#seo">Content Creation + SEO</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#ppc">Landing Pages + PPC</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
 	<li><a href="#onboarding">New Member Onboarding</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#upgrade">Upgrade Campaigns</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#referral">Referral Campaigns</a></li>
 	<li><a href="#renewal">Renewal Campaigns</a></li>
</ol>
<h2 id="journey">Outline Your Members’ Journey</h2>
<span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Discovery</strong></span> | Onboarding | Engagement | Renewal

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-15562 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/value-copy-28@2x.jpg" alt="membership journey mapping" width="1920" height="1030" />

Like a customer journey, a member has a journey of their own at your organization.

A members’ journey is the outlining of every interaction and stage of their involvement with your organization from discovery to renewal of their membership.

Start by identifying your target audience, and then chopping up your organization’s interaction with them into stages so you can better plan for each want and need a person in your journey has.

Broken-down, it looks like this:
<ol>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Discovery</strong></span></li>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Onboarding</strong></span></li>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Engagement</strong></span></li>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Renewal</strong></span></li>
</ol>
Depending on your organization’s structure and membership these stages may differ, but generally this is what a member in your organization experiences in their lifetime as a member.

Breaking it down in this fashion allows you to better plan what specific marketing campaigns are needed, what content or language is needed, and which marketing method or tool is appropriate.

For the purposes of this article, we’ll stick with the basic stages above.
<h2 id="software">Using the Right Software</h2>
<span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Discovery</strong></span> | Onboarding | Engagement | Renewal

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16783 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/eventbank-blog-roundb@2x-1.png" alt="membership management software" width="1920" height="1030" />

It’s time to start identifying the software, tools, and platforms that can help your organization both personalize and scale-up its ability to promote, engage, and retain members.

There are different tools that may exist in all stages, or just some stages, of the member-journey.
The basics include:
<ul>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>CRM</strong></span></li>
 	<li><strong><span style="color: #00b832;">Email Marketing</span></strong></li>
 	<li><strong><span style="color: #00b832;">Event Management Software</span></strong></li>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Your Website</strong></span></li>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Social Media</strong></span></li>
 	<li><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Payment Tools</strong></span></li>
</ul>
In your search for tools and providers, you might be interested in all-in-one software that combines the majority of these tools into one platform so it’s an easy place to own your data and use it to make smarter member-marketing campaigns. Check out our <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/best-membership-management-software/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">membership management tools comparison</a> for more details.

We’ll be mentioning along with this article which tools to use and where in the journey they would work best.
<h2 id="outbound">Outbound Member Campaigns</h2>
<span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Discovery</strong></span> | Onboarding | Engagement | Renewal

Software: A CRM, Membership Management Software

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-3292 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Email-Campaigns-Ad-Copy@2x.png" alt="event email marketing guide" width="1920" height="1030" />

In marketing, there are <span style="color: #00b832;"><b>outbound</b></span> and <span style="color: #00b832;"><b>inbound</b></span> campaigns that help drive new customers, and in essence, your members are your customers.

In outbound campaigns, these are essentially the cold-calling and cold-emailing phase of any business, or any other outreach activity.

This also would include attending events, conferences, and webinars for the purposed of creating relationships with people directly.

Effectively your outbound campaigns are your manual efforts to reach out and convert your target audience into paying members.

There are smarter ways to go about it however that can scale up your outreach.
<h3 id="email">CRMs + Email Outreach Campaigns</h3>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17341 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/emails-blog@2x.png" alt="webinar invite email examples" width="2400" height="1288" />

Email campaigns are by far and large one of the most effective ways to reach out to your target audience, provided you have a contact database, to begin with.

It’s important to have a CRM software in place, and there are some options available for free or at reasonable prices.

A CRM is more than just a place to manage your contacts, most retail CRMs like Salesforce, Hubspot, or <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">all-in-one CRMs like EventBank’s</a>, have functionality to integrate your contact database with email campaign tools.

Why do you want to integrate?

It helps personalize all your communication at a larger scale.

What does personalization look like?

At an advanced level, a drafted, personalized email looks like this:
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-18685 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Email-example-with-shadow.png" alt="membership email campaign example" width="774" height="312" />
You’ll notice some things called “<span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>merge tags</strong></span>” or “<span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>personalization properties</strong></span>”, or other terms. These are essentially tiny code snippets easily added to email drafts that both personalize emails with any field from their CRM profile.

In layman’s terms, you can refer to their first name in the salutation of the email for any contact’s email that is delivered your email campaign.

This can be expanded to more complex emails like calling out their company name if it’s available, their city name, and more.

If some fields aren’t available you can fall-back to some generic words so long as it fits the sentence grammar.

This means you can craft extremely <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>personalized emails that look genuine</strong></span> and are less likely to be seen as spam by both email firewalls and recipients at first glance.

Open rates should be better, click through, replies, and conversion rates should also be much better.

There’s no real way to personalize without a CRM, so be sure you do some shopping to know which tools work best together. Alternatively, a <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">membership management software solution</a> will also have this functionality.

It’s best to choose a CRM first, and then look for their integrations page, and then follow the trail until you find an affordable tool for you.

Or, just look for an all-in-one software solution for membership-based organizations that integrate natively and internally for a hassle-free user experience for yourself.
<h3 id="socialnetworking">Social Media Networking</h3>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-18418 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sponsorships.png" alt="webinar sponsorship guide" width="1200" height="644" />

Fairly simple, start networking on LinkedIn or other social media where your audience is active, and start engaging with the community.

Don’t jump out of the gates offering your organization’s membership, but do engage and make friends.

It’s a great way to exchange contact info earnestly and create more genuine contacts in your database, give great public image for your organization, and also be in-the-know with your audience.
<h3 id="events">Events &amp; Conference Networking</h3>
<strong>Software</strong>: <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">Event Management Software</a>; A CRM with Business Card Scanning (optional)

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16672 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/value-copy-58@1x.png" alt="conference networking tips" width="1200" height="644" />

Exactly like LinkedIn Networking, you should attend events where your audience is active, or webinars in the case of 2020, and start networking.

Some CRMs even have a feature that lets you take pictures of upwards of 20 business cards laid-out on a table, and the CRM will read each business card and upload the contact data directly to your database.

Don’t forget you can also host your own events that drive people to you, register online, and you can collect their contact information automatically with the use of event management software.
<h2 id="inbound">Inbound Member Campaigns</h2>
<span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Discovery</strong></span> | Onboarding | Engagement | Renewal

<strong>Software</strong>: Your Website, Ads Accounts, a CRM

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17237 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/8-strategies-community@2x.png" alt="social connections eventbank" width="2400" height="1288" />

The opposite of outbound campaigns, inbound campaigns is how you pull your audience to you.

From as generic as brand-building for your organization, to as intricate as search engine optimization and online ads.

This can be a bit complicated and technical, so we’ll keep it simple as can be.
<h3 id="socialpresence">Social Media Presence</h3>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-17934 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/survey-webinar@2x.png" alt="webinar survey questions" width="1920" height="1030" />

Like our advice about social media networking in outbound campaigns, it’s important to also create pages or business pages in social media, mainly Twitter, LinkedIn, and Facebook.

Having a presence at an official capacity alone helps bring your audience to you, and creates more channels for growth.

Post through your official account with experiences, tips, guides, reports, and kudos to other users, and you’ll soon grow a social following that can convert into members easily.
<h3 id="seo">Content Creation + SEO</h3>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16661 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/value-copy-20@2x.png" alt="chamber of commerce myths and misconceptions" width="1920" height="1030" />

Content creation can be a variety of things, but it’s important to have them with SEO in mind.

SEO is Search Engine Optimization. It’s how you create web pages that can be found easily on search engines like Google, Bing, or Yahoo.

There’s two parts to SEO, how technically healthy the web page is, and how high quality your content is.

<span style="color: #00b832;"><b>Let’s start with content quality</b></span>, as it’s easy to create and replicate, with some love and care.

Content creation with your competitors. Let’s start with a blogging strategy.

If you want to write a blog post, instead of thinking of ideas of what to write yourself, the best thing to do is find out what your competitors are writing, and which of their blogs are successful.

Free tools like <a href="http://ubersuggest.com">Ubersuggest</a> and <a href="http://semrush.com">SEM Rush</a> are great for helping you crawl competitor sites (as well as your own) and determind which of their articles are performing best, and what keyword they’re targeting.

Just plug in your competitor's website, and it'll show you their top pages and which keywords they target like this:

[caption id="attachment_18693" align="aligncenter" width="1062"]<img class="wp-image-18693 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/SEO-research.png" alt="seo research for memberships" width="1062" height="376" /> If we were Lyft, we'd make this type of analysis against our competitor, Uber.[/caption]

If they keyword is relevant, and it should be, because they’re a competitor, then open their blog article, web page, or landing page, and start researching how they write the content, the purpose, and their flair they use to make it stand out.

Your job now is to simply <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>replicate this content</strong></span>, <em>but do a much better job than them</em>.

If they have a list of 20 hackathon ideas, then you should produce <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/hackathon-ideas/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">30 hackathon ideas</a>. More ideas means more value for the reader in this case.

In other cases, try to see google searches through your audience’s eyes, if they want a guide on how to do <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/fundraising-ideas/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">fundraisers</a> for instance and your competitor has 20 steps to complete it, then you should break it down to 10 steps in whichever way you can do it.

Less steps is more time savings, thus giving value to the reader.

More content doesn’t always mean a higher-performing blog post on search engines, so try to understand what the searcher is looking for before coming up with better competitive content.

Remember to write to give value to the reader in ways that beat your competition, and search engines will reward you with higher ranking.

It doesn’t have to be blogs either, you can create infographics, online calculators, videos, and other cool content on your website too.

Don’t forget to share it on social media when you’ve published your hard work!

Technical SEO is a bit complicated, and if you’re not familiar with it, just <a href="https://www.semrush.com/blog/seo-best-practices/">relay this great article to your web developer</a> and let them determine the next actions.

Technical SEO needs the basics to rank, and it can help if you know more advanced SEO best practices, but ultimately, as long as you reach bare minimum SEO requirements without hurting your website, high-quality content will always grow.

SEO takes time, and it’s a long-term marketing activity that shouldn’t be given up on early.

<em>It could take up to one year</em> before you see some meaningful traction online, but trust us, as long as you trust in your content, adjust where needed, and update content regularly, you’ll see the fruits of your labor.
<h3 id="ppc">Landing Pages + PPC Ads</h3>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16470 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-2@2x-2.png" alt="marketing trends in 2020" width="1920" height="1030" />

Landing pages are pages that help funnel visitors to your website from other channels, or even directly through being seen on search engines.

Essentially, these can be replicated website homepages with different or stylized content that’s meant for specific keywords or channels.

Here’s what ours look like.

These pages act to encourage conversion of visitors into new membership registrations, but to get them in this funnel you’ve created, it’s more targeted to just use ads.

Both on Social Media and Search Engines, you can create Ads accounts that let you purchase either posts on social media that reach larger audiences, or search ads that show up at the top of search results for keywords you choose.

These ads target keywords that you might have identified in your SEO research above when targeting competitors.

Thusly, the ads should link to your landing page, which would also consist of a content-focus on those keywords as well.

Here’s <a href="https://www.crazyegg.com/blog/landing-page-optimization/">a neat guide to creating landing pages</a>, but be sure to think about membership registrations in mind, as more tutorials will have products or demos in mind when showing landing page examples.

<span style="text-decoration: underline;">Ads are a granular and on-going activity.</span>

Small budgets will have small results, big budgets will have a higher risk of failure. But both can be avoided if you can nurture your ads, identify ads that are failing, and improve and change up content of the ads or landing pages over time.

Soon you should have a working Pay Per Click engine that produces results.
<h2 id="onboarding">New Member Onboarding</h2>
Discovery | <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Onboarding</strong></span> | Engagement | Renewal

<strong>Software</strong>: Membership Management Software

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16091 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/value-copy-57@2x.png" alt="membership strategy" width="1920" height="1030" />

Onboarding a new member is a marketing activity in it of itself. It may be more intrinsic to your organization’s operations and member services than your actual active marketing strategy.

But in-all, the onboarding procedure should be aimed at engaging them early on and getting hyped about being a member. This can get them to:
<ul>
 	<li>Invite their friends to become members too</li>
 	<li>Share their hype at becoming a member on social</li>
 	<li>Reduce post-payment regret</li>
</ul>
The on-boarding experience differs from organization to organization, so we’ll leave it up to you to decide the method of on-boarding or what content to use.

Some advice we can give will be to use a <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">membership management software</a>, more than a CRM, it’s likely a part of an all-in-one software solution that helps to manage contacts not as customers, but as members that can track their history of engagement with your organziation, automate reminders, and automatically renew memberships.

There are even platforms out there that can help deliver digital membership cards that help with the member’s interaction with your organization, any physical locations you might own that have access card needs, and are just all-around more convenient to have over physical membership cards. Check out our guide on <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/digital-membership-cards/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">how digital membership cards work</a> for more details.

Among this, it’s important to also deliver some <a href="http://blog.eventbank.com/swag-bag-ideas/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">goodie-bags</a> that help welcome them!
<h2 id="upgrade">Upgrade Marketing Campaigns</h2>
Discovery | Onboarding | <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Engagement</strong></span> | Renewal

<strong>Software</strong>: Email Marketing, CRM, SMS, Membership Management Software

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16137 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/value-copy-58@2x.png" alt="key members" width="1920" height="1030" />

This is an optional marketing strategy for organizations with different levels of membership packages.

When creating your membership journey outline, it’s important to identify the time at which you feel it’s appropriate to send campaigns to members that would help them upgrade their membership.

Maybe members who are about to renew their membership in a lower tier could be shown the benefits of not just renewing, but upgrading.

If you have an all-in-one membership software, then you could ideally identify engaged members with a discounted upgrade offer.

For instance, if they attended more than 80% of events you held in a year, you can offer a discounted upgrade.

Or maybe they referred a new member, we’ll get into this in the next section.

Email is by far the easiest method to use to reach out to members with these campaigns as you can easily assign lists made with the requirements you had in your membership software for who is eligible for offers, as well as the timeframe of their membership.

You can use other alternatives to send the campaign like SMS, Social Media posts, and even mailed letters.
<h2 id="referral">Referral Campaigns</h2>
Discovery | Onboarding | <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Engagement</strong></span> | Renewal

<strong>Software</strong>: Email Marketing, CRM, SMS, Membership Management Software

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-16140 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/value-copy-61@2x-1.png" alt="contact management" width="1920" height="1030" />

As we eluded to before this section, a referral program can act as a great catalyst to encourage new member acquisition.

Word of mouth is by far an large the best method of convincing your audience to convert into members.

A referral campaign simply rewards those for spreading the word about your organization, or otherwise encourages more people to talk about it and invite their friends and colleagues to join too.

Marketing for your organization essentially becomes easier at this point.

Now it’s a simple question of what are you willing to give to current members that reward them for referring new members to join?

You’ve had experience in the earlier stages of this guide with outbound, inbound, and upgrade campaigns, so it’s not a question now of how you should reach out to members with a referral program, but simply what is the program itself made of.

Maybe members in a tiered membership organization will enjoy a half-off discount to upgrade to a higher tier if they refer one or more members.

Potentially they can obtain gifts, privileges, or other goodies for referring new members.

The choice becomes yours at this point, and this extends to Renewal campaigns as well.
<h2 id="renewal">Renewal Campaigns</h2>
Discovery | Onboarding | Engagement | <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Renewal</strong></span>

<strong>Software</strong>: Email Marketing, CRM, SMS, Membership Management Software

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-12227 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/vr-article-copy-65@2x.png" alt="chamber invitation email" width="1920" height="1030" />

Very much like referral campaigns, this is a simple marketing strategy that helps encourage members to renew.

Now, ideally you’ve done a great job in the past steps of this guide that you don’t need to use a campaign to encourage renewals, but still, there are some best practices you need to use just in case.

The main best practice that should be used no matter how much your members love your organization, is to have an automatic email or push-notification reminder sent to your members who are within one month (or whichever time-frame you determine) of their membership expiry date.

This will help enter them into an automatic email or push notification journey that can send periodical notifications that their membership is expiring and that they should renew before time runs out.

You will not always be doting over your members manually, and it will be very easy to miss out on members who are close to expiring. Having this on autopilot is a great way to take the pressure off.

More manually, you can send campaigns to past members who expired or canceled with new offers that could encourage them to join once more, however, this is where it's important to have CRM or <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">membership management software</a> that helps identify such lists that contain members who are no longer members.
<h2>That’s That</h2>
We hope this guide was helpful in giving you ideas to start with, the tools to use, and the strategies to bend to your organization’s needs and help you both obtain and retain members for the foreseeable future.

We mentioned a range of tools in this article, and while it can be nice to do the research, it’s becoming easier and more accessible to just implement <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">an all-in-one membership management software solution</a> inside your organization that has all these tools and software mentioned, and more.

Consider <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=membershipmarketing">booking a demo</a> with EventBank, and we’ll show you how our platform helps you manage and market your membership offers to your audience.
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Or book a demo through the form below</strong></span></p>
[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]

<a href="#top"><strong>Back to Page Top</strong></a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18678</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-07-17 07:54:23]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-07-17 07:54:23]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[membership-marketing-guide]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="digital-marketing"><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="marketing"><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="membership-management"><![CDATA[membership management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="membership-marketing"><![CDATA[membership marketing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[41]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Ultimate Guide to Membership Marketing]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Ultimate Guide to Membership Marketing that helps your organization obtain and retain members for a truly well-rounded membership marketing experience.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18700]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>18 Strategies to Increase Donations to Your Organzation</title>
		<link>http://blog.eventbank.com/increase-donations/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 07:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[carl]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.eventbank.com/?p=18708</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Increasing donations to your organization is an obvious strategy that any cause needs to get off the ground. Donations are sometimes an integral part of some organizations and they may be used to benefit other fundraisers. Regardless of why your organization asks for donations, <span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>asking people to donate money to your organization is no easy task</strong></span>.
<h2>What to Keep In Mind</h2>
Asking for donations is not the easiest process for raising money for your organization, but it doesn't need to be the hardest.

One simple fact of the matter is that the first step of each donation you receive comes with capturing your audience’s attention.

In our fast-paced, short attention span society, this is not an easy task, however, there are strategies involved to capture your audiences’ attention and keep them interested.

The more donors you keep interested and attract, the more donations you will be receiving.
<h3>Quick Reads</h3>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="#email">Email Campaigns</a>
<a href="#text">Text Message Campaigns</a>
<a href="#snail">Snail Mail Campaigns</a>
<a href="#fb">Facebook</a>
<a href="#gram">Instagram</a>
<a href="#in">LinkedIn</a>
<a href="#blog">Blog</a>
<a href="#soft">Donation Software</a>
<a href="#multi">Multiple Platforms</a></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="#stories">Compelling Stories</a>
<a href="#recurring">Recurring Donations</a>
<a href="#charity">Charity Events</a>
<a href="#personalize">Personalized Messages</a>
<a href="#thank">Thank You Notes</a>
<a href="#peer">Peer-to-Peer</a>
<a href="#review">Share Reviews</a>
<a href="#share">Share Stories</a>
<a href="#Progress">Share Progress</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Email &amp; SMS Campaigns</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16771" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/eventbank-blog@2x.png" alt="in person event seminars" width="1920" height="1030" />

Written fundraising campaigns are important because they are able to spread a larger quantity of information regarding your donation campaign in one letter.

Recurring written campaigns can also consistently remind potential donors about current campaigns as well as future ones.

This can help remind your donors to give donations, increasing the number of donations you accept.
<h3 id="email">1. Email Campaigns</h3>
Email Campaigns to subscribers can help inform donors of past/current/future campaigns.

Using this platform you can write emails that can educate and motivate your donors to make donations. Different email formats can include:
<ol>
 	<li>An email about a new campaign coming up</li>
 	<li>Updates on a current campaign</li>
 	<li>End of campaign</li>
 	<li>Past campaign success stories</li>
 	<li>Weekly emails to keep donors engaged between campaigns</li>
</ol>
Ensure that your donation link always includes somewhere easily visible for your donors when they open their emails.

In addition, verify that the format can be read in both mobile and desktop because around half the population reads their emails on a mobile device.
<h3 id="text">2. Text Message Campaigns</h3>
Text messages are the best way to reach people in today’s day and age.

Since <strong><span style="color: #00b832;">people check their phones once every</span> <a href="https://nypost.com/2017/11/08/americans-check-their-phones-80-times-a-day-study/">12 minutes</a></strong>, it is the best way to capture your donor’s attention and ensure that they see your messages.

If you have a CRM database you will likely have all your previous donor’s phone numbers so it will be easy to send an automated text to ask for donations.
<h3 id="Snail">3. Snail Mail Campaigns</h3>
Snail Mail has been in decreasing use over the past few years as technology, email, and instant messaging have been used in a higher volume.

However, this does not mean that sending campaigns through snail mail is not a useful strategy.

Your donors are receiving less snail mail now so this means you will have less competition if you send your campaigns in this format.

This will mean that your donors are more likely to have their attention captured when you send them a donation campaign through this medium.
<h2>Social Media Campaigns</h2>
<img class="aligncenter wp-image-15303 size-full" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/eventbank-exploration-patterns-8-copy-8@2x.png" alt="membership social media" width="1920" height="1030" />

Social Media is prevalent in our society today.

People spend around <strong><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/433871/daily-social-media-usage-worldwide/#:~:text=As%20of%202019%2C%20the%20average,minutes%20in%20the%20previous%20year">144 minutes</a></strong> on social media per day.

This high volume of time spent on social media means that your potential donors could be attained through this platform, increasing your donations.
<h3 id="fb">4. Facebook</h3>
With over <strong><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide/#:~:text=How%20many%20users%20does%20Facebook,network%20ever%20to%20do%20so">2.6 billion monthly</a> </strong>users on its platform, Facebook is a great way to spread the word to your donors on your campaigns.

You can host a page for your organization and with Facebook’s integrated donation widget, you can accept donations straight through Facebook.

However, it can be hard to be seen by your donors through all the clutter on Facebook. To clear the clutter and be sure to show in people’s feeds, you can create a Facebook ad that integrates your donation request.
<h3 id="">5. Instagram</h3>
Instagram, unlike Facebook, can be overlooked when creating social media campaigns.

However, Instagram has over <strong><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/253577/number-of-monthly-active-instagram-users/">1 billion users </a></strong>and continues to grow. Using Instagram Donation Sticker in the stories function for your organization can not only promote your campaign but collect donations straight from the platform as well.
<h3 id="in">6. LinkedIn</h3>
LinkedIn has a separate account for non-profit organizations. Using this account you can use their fundraising tools to capture new donors as well as convincing you donors to give you increasing donations.
<h3 id="blog">7. Blogging</h3>
Utilizing a blog can attract new donors as well as update your current donors about the progress in your campaigns.

Write multiple blog posts throughout the campaign and incorporate photos or videos that can influence your donors' emotions to donate more.

This keeps your donor base active and updated on the progress of your campaigns and organizations
<h2>Internal Strategy</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16516" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eventbank-exploration-patterns-1-copy-dfsdsd-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-copy-3@2x.png" alt="chambers and associations" width="1920" height="1030" />

Changes in your internal strategy can also increase the donations you accept. Making the right strategic choices can benefit your organization greatly.
<h3 id="soft">8. Use Donation Software</h3>
Using donation software not only helps you manage your donations and contacts but also helps you pick up new leads on potential donors that are likely to be more philanthropic.

With a large amount of donation software out there, you need to <a href="https://blog.eventbank.com/donation-software/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=increasedonations">pick the right one</a> for your needs. Using the right donation software you can increase the number of donations you receive in an automated fashion.
<h3 id="multi">9. Multiple Donation Platforms</h3>
Using only one platform such as email campaigns is not conducive to spreading the word and collecting large amounts of donations.

Using multiple donation platforms can attract different demographics and spread the word about your campaign in different ways.

Users of Instagram and Snail Mail would be very demographics, but reaching out to both expand the number of potential donors, which then increases the number of donations you receive.
<h3 id="stories">10. Tell Compelling Stories</h3>
Compelling stories that your organization can tell can drive donors to donate more.

Spreading these stories can create an emotional response for people to feel the need to donate in order to feel better about themselves.

Use these stories on your campaigns that illustrate how the donations can end up helping those in need.
<h3 id="recurring">11. Recurring Donations</h3>
Having a donor sign up for recurring donations is an easy way to increase your donations.

With many businesses today switching to subscriptions for their entertainment, people are used to paying for things on a monthly basis, so why not donations.

Recurring Donations will make it easier for your organization because each month the donation will automatically come without any additional campaigns that you would need to spend your time on.

This gives your organization time to devote to finding new donors to increase donations
<h3 id="charity">12. Charity Events</h3>
Hosting Charity Events is a great way to increase donations in person.

These events put people in the mindset of being in a giving mood when they arrive, and so when asking for donations when they are already in the set mood, they will be a higher chance for them to contribute a larger donation.
<h2>Personalize the Donation Process</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17341" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/emails-blog@2x.png" alt="webinar invite email examples" width="2400" height="1288" />

Personalizing your donation process can help your donors feel more connected to your organization.

This sense of connection can increase sales and donations and improve relationships with current donors.
<h3 id="personalize">13. Personalized Messages</h3>
Personalized messages will help increase donations because they are directed at the specific donor.

This overrules the bystander effect which leads people to believe someone else would help so they do not need to.

When being addressed directly, people are less inclined to avoid giving a donation.
<h3 id="thank">14. Thank You Notes</h3>
Thank you notes show gratitude to your donors in supporting your organization.

These types of notes show that you value your donor’s contribution which will give them more reason to keep on giving.
<h2>Word of Mouth</h2>
<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17237" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/8-strategies-community@2x.png" alt="social connections eventbank" width="2400" height="1288" />

Why do all the work if your donors can also spread the message of your campaign for you?

Letting your donors spread the word and fundraise for you give your organization more time to search for new potential donors.
<h3 id="peer">15. Peer-to-Peer</h3>
Peer-to-peer fundraising allows your donors to fundraise on your behalf.

This allows them to spread the word about your campaigns without your organization needs to put in much work.

This way more potential donors see the campaign and will be more likely to donate.
<h3 id="review">16. Supporters Reviews</h3>
Posting supporter reviews is another way to let the donors do the talking.

This allows future potential donors to see the positive experiences previous donors had, to convince them also donate to your organization
<h3 id="share">17. Share Stories</h3>
Sharing stories about where the donations go and who they help makes the donations feel more real.

This allows the donors to make a connection to the difference they are making in the world. This convinces donors that donating to your organization actually is making a difference.
<h3 id="progress">18. Share Progress</h3>
Sharing the progress of your donors’ donations will incentivizing your donors to help you reach your goal.

This gamification strategy for donations creates a fun way for your donors to donate more because they can see the donations slowly reaching your goal, and could low-key implant an endorphin-inducing visual that could make a few key donors donate more to reach the goal if you're ever-close to it.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-18418" src="http://blog.eventbank.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sponsorships.png" alt="webinar sponsorship guide" width="1200" height="644" />
<h2>Wrapping It Up</h2>
Each of these strategies can be implemented to increase donations for your fundraising campaigns, however, some may work better than others for your specific organizations.

Look for what your organization is missing and what it needs to pick the best strategies to improve your campaigns.

If you come up with any other tips let us know! We hope you all the best in your fundraising campaigns!

If you're looking for an all-in-one software that not only helps manage and promote your donation campaigns, but set up events, webinars, manage contacts, and more, consider <a href="http://get.eventbank.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=increasedonations">booking a demo</a> with EventBank to see how our platform has helped organizations like yours run amazing events and make smarter decisions.
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #00b832;"><strong>Or book a demo through the form below</strong></span></p>
[contact-form-7 id="3235" title="freebies english"]

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18708</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2020-07-24 07:19:17]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2020-07-24 07:19:17]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[increase-donations]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="donation"><![CDATA[donation]]></category>
		<category domain="language" nicename="en"><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="event-management"><![CDATA[Event Management]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="fundraiser"><![CDATA[fundraiser]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="fundraising-campaign"><![CDATA[fundraising campaign]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[25]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[increase donations]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[71]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18 Strategies to Increase Donations to Your Organzation]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18 Strategies to Increase Donations to Your Organzation and get any cause off the ground. Bring in donors, engage past donors, and break through goals!]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[18729]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
	